{
    "questions": [
        {
            "id": 376,
            "question": "Burch and Daniel are best friends, playing on opposing teams. \u00a0Daniel is guarding the goal and Burch has a clear shot. Then he remembers it's Daniel's birthday...and he misses the shot for his best friend...",
            "options": [
                "A. retrodiction",
                "C. chiromancy",
                "D. mercalli scale",
                "B. point shaving"
            ],
            "answer": "B. point shaving",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 193,
            "question": "In the early 1800s, two German brothers gathered and published folk tales which had been handed down over generations. Their collections of stories included \"Hansel and Gretel\", \"Rapunzel\", \"Little Red Riding Hood\" among many others. Which brothers brought us these fairy tales? ",
            "options": [
                "The Basile Brothers",
                "The Heidelburg Brothers",
                "The Brothers Grimm",
                "The Brothers Brown"
            ],
            "answer": "The Brothers Grimm",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 286,
            "question": "Name the boxer thats knocked down",
            "options": [
                "Felix Trinidad",
                "Edwin Valero",
                "Fernando Vargas",
                "Ricardo Mayorga"
            ],
            "answer": "Ricardo Mayorga",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 394,
            "question": "Where was Napoleon born?",
            "options": [
                "Majorca",
                "Sicily",
                "Isle of Man",
                "Corsica"
            ],
            "answer": "Corsica",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 442,
            "question": "In a coon's ______.",
            "options": [
                "Night",
                "Moon",
                "Age",
                "Song"
            ],
            "answer": "Age",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 57,
            "question": "What religion is the most practiced one in India?",
            "options": [
                "Shinto",
                "Hinduism",
                "Islam",
                "Sikhism "
            ],
            "answer": "Hinduism",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 318,
            "question": "Select the years Nick Faldo won the masters?",
            "options": [
                "1996",
                "1990",
                "1992",
                "1989"
            ],
            "answer": "1989",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 377,
            "question": "What is true about Ragnarok?",
            "options": [
                "A. it is a myth",
                "B. it is about the moon",
                "C. It is Nordic (Norse) in origin",
                "E. it is the  final Norse battle which will kill the main gods."
            ],
            "answer": "E. it is the  final Norse battle which will kill the main gods.",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 140,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Four Agreements\"?",
            "options": [
                "Don Miguel Ruiz",
                "Maxine Hong",
                "Ken Kesey",
                "Joan Didion"
            ],
            "answer": "Don Miguel Ruiz",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 374,
            "question": "Which of these are said to be &#34;facts&#34; about \u00a0Paul McCartney?",
            "options": [
                "A, he secretly died & the Beatles hired a look-alike named Billy Shears",
                "B. Yoko Ono did it",
                "C.  he was supposedly killed in a car crash",
                "E. there are a lot of clues through the Beatles' albums and music"
            ],
            "answer": "E. there are a lot of clues through the Beatles' albums and music",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 123,
            "question": "What character was most like Stalin?",
            "options": [
                "Napoleon",
                "Mollie ",
                "Snowball",
                "Boxer"
            ],
            "answer": "Napoleon",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 381,
            "question": "He allegedly faced his death, performed under the stage name Makaveli \u00a0named after Niccolo Machiavelli <font color=\"#2d3639\">. E</font>veryone (over) analyzed his lyrics once he died<br style=\"color: rgb(45, 54, 57);\"/>\u00a0Some people believe that he fled to Cuba (where his aunt Assata lives) after faking his death<br style=\"color: rgb(45, 54, 57);\"/><br/>",
            "options": [
                "A. Kurt Cobain",
                "B. Elvis Presley",
                "D. Paul McCartney",
                "C. Tupac"
            ],
            "answer": "C. Tupac",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 219,
            "question": "The periodic symbol for Iron is?",
            "options": [
                "NaCl",
                "K",
                "Hg",
                "Fe"
            ],
            "answer": "Fe",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 9,
            "question": "Which actor appeared in the Cranberries music video Ridiculous Thought?",
            "options": [
                "Bruce Willis",
                "Donald Sutherland",
                "George Clooney",
                "Elijah Wood"
            ],
            "answer": "Elijah Wood",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 170,
            "question": "Who arrives at the Capulet's tomb first?",
            "options": [
                "Friar Laurence",
                "Paris",
                "Lord Capulet",
                "Romeo"
            ],
            "answer": "Paris",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 26,
            "question": "In the book The Last Of The Mohicans what was the name of Chingachgook's only son?",
            "options": [
                "Mingo",
                "Lightfoot",
                "Magua",
                "Uncas"
            ],
            "answer": "Uncas",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 371,
            "question": "According to Moore's law, what happens every 18 month?",
            "options": [
                "A. the earth changes orbit",
                "B. an assassination takes place",
                "D. a new virus is created",
                "C. computer power doubles"
            ],
            "answer": "C. computer power doubles",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 151,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Godfather\"?",
            "options": [
                "Edward Ball",
                "Theodore Dreiser",
                "Don Miguel Ruiz",
                "Mario Puzo"
            ],
            "answer": "Mario Puzo",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 384,
            "question": "Around what year did the Romans overthrow the kings and establish the Republic?",
            "options": [
                "400 BC",
                "600 BC",
                "300 BC",
                "500 BC"
            ],
            "answer": "500 BC",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 468,
            "question": "\"I have friends in overalls whose friendship I would not swap for the favour of the kings of the world.\" Born in 1847, who said this?",
            "options": [
                "Eli Whitney",
                "Thomas Edison",
                "Dr Frankenstein",
                "Isaac Newton"
            ],
            "answer": "Thomas Edison",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 66,
            "question": "What is the name for the Jewish New Year?",
            "options": [
                "Yom Kippur",
                "Rosh Hashanah",
                "Hanukkah",
                "Kwanzaa "
            ],
            "answer": "Rosh Hashanah",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 154,
            "question": "Who wrote \"And Then There Were None\"?",
            "options": [
                "Agatha Christie",
                "James Baldwin",
                "Richard Bach",
                "Linda Hogan"
            ],
            "answer": "Agatha Christie",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 426,
            "question": "He is head over ______.",
            "options": [
                "Wheels",
                "Blues",
                "Heels",
                "Shoes"
            ],
            "answer": "Heels",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 457,
            "question": "\"Courage is what it takes to stand up and speak, Courage is also what it takes to sit down and listen\"",
            "options": [
                "Theodore Roosevelt",
                "George Washington",
                "Albert Einstein",
                "Winston Churchill"
            ],
            "answer": "Winston Churchill",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 428,
            "question": "There are many paths to the top of the mountain but the ______ is always the same.",
            "options": [
                "Flight",
                "View",
                "Distance",
                "Trail"
            ],
            "answer": "View",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 358,
            "question": "Which of these are true about the assassination of Julius Caesar?",
            "options": [
                "A. daggers were the weapon of choice",
                "B. it was driven by the fear of the end of  the Roman Empire",
                "C. it resulted in Caesar getting stabbed 35 times",
                "E. It took place in the Roman Senate"
            ],
            "answer": "E. It took place in the Roman Senate",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 446,
            "question": "Busy as a ______.",
            "options": [
                "Bear",
                "Bird",
                "Fly",
                "Bee"
            ],
            "answer": "Bee",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 168,
            "question": "What happens after the Friar tells the truth to the Prince?",
            "options": [
                "We don't know for sure",
                "He is excommunicated",
                "He is killed",
                "He is banished"
            ],
            "answer": "We don't know for sure",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 5,
            "question": "'Goodbye Farewell and Amen' was the final episode of which TV series?",
            "options": [
                "MASH",
                "Dallas",
                "Friends",
                "The Muppet Show"
            ],
            "answer": "MASH",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 331,
            "question": "The Taj Mahal (India) built by Mughal emperor Shah Jahan in memory of his third wife was finished construction in what year?",
            "options": [
                "1553",
                "1453",
                "1353",
                "1653"
            ],
            "answer": "1653",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 234,
            "question": "The face through which molecules enter the golgi apparatus is called the __________ face. ",
            "options": [
                "Dorsal",
                "Trans",
                "Cis ",
                "Medial"
            ],
            "answer": "Cis ",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 481,
            "question": "The goddess of agriculture, horticulture, grain and harvest.",
            "options": [
                "Demeter",
                "Pluto/Hades",
                "Ares",
                "Hera"
            ],
            "answer": "Demeter",
            "category_id": 10
        },
        {
            "id": 28,
            "question": "In which continent did the ostrich originate?",
            "options": [
                "Africa",
                "Australia",
                "North America",
                "Asia"
            ],
            "answer": "Africa",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 138,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Art of War\"?",
            "options": [
                "Sun Tzu",
                "Alice Walker",
                "Erica Jong",
                "Joan Didion"
            ],
            "answer": "Sun Tzu",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 7,
            "question": "What is the name of the man servant in 'Around the world in 80 days'?",
            "options": [
                "Pas Partout",
                "Cato",
                "Giles",
                "Machu Picchu"
            ],
            "answer": "Pas Partout",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 320,
            "question": "Which sport isn't played on ice?",
            "options": [
                "Shorttrack ",
                "Bobsledding ",
                "Curling ",
                "Lacrosse "
            ],
            "answer": "Lacrosse ",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 153,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Celestine Prophecy\"?",
            "options": [
                "Charles Dickens",
                "Alice Walker",
                "James Redfield",
                "Raymond Carver"
            ],
            "answer": "James Redfield",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 2,
            "question": "James Bond was searching for what kind of airplane in 'Thunderball'?",
            "options": [
                "707",
                "Piper Cub",
                "Vulkan",
                "B-52"
            ],
            "answer": "Vulkan",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 472,
            "question": "\"No pessimist ever discovered the secret of the stars, or sailed to an uncharted land, or opened a new heaven to the human spirit.\" Which great woman deprived of her sight and hearing, made this observation?",
            "options": [
                "Helen Keller",
                "Joan of Arc",
                "Audrey Hepburn",
                "Mary, Queen of Scots"
            ],
            "answer": "Helen Keller",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 83,
            "question": "What does M stand for in Roman Numerals?",
            "options": [
                "1,000,000",
                "100",
                "10",
                "1000"
            ],
            "answer": "1000",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 187,
            "question": "In the classic short story entitled \"The Legend of Sleepy Hollow\", a new schoolteacher comes to town. He's an awkward and rather unattractive man. He falls in love with a beautiful young woman, and is rejected by her as they attend a party. On his way hom",
            "options": [
                "Ichabod Crane",
                "Bob Cratchit",
                "Rip Van Winkle",
                "Nicolas Nickleby"
            ],
            "answer": "Ichabod Crane",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 288,
            "question": "In which round did Robert Duran say 'no mas' to Ray Leonard ?",
            "options": [
                "12",
                "6",
                "8",
                "10"
            ],
            "answer": "8",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 133,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Selfish Gene\"?",
            "options": [
                "Joan Didion",
                "Nicholas Evans",
                "Kenneth Grahame",
                "Richard Dawkins"
            ],
            "answer": "Richard Dawkins",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 466,
            "question": " \"If you could kick the person in the pants responsible for most of your trouble, you wouldn't sit for a month.\" Which great American President said this?",
            "options": [
                "Foghorn Leghorn",
                "Theodore Roosevelt",
                "Richard Nixon",
                "Bill Clinton"
            ],
            "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 420,
            "question": "______ no bones about it.",
            "options": [
                "Shake",
                "Make",
                "Take",
                "Break"
            ],
            "answer": "Make",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 456,
            "question": "\"And as we let our own light shine, we unconsciously give other people permission to do the same\"",
            "options": [
                "Nelson Mandela",
                "Mother Teresa",
                "Jesus Christ ",
                "Mahatma Gandhi"
            ],
            "answer": "Nelson Mandela",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 433,
            "question": "Every ______ has a silver lining.",
            "options": [
                "Wish",
                "Dream",
                "Education",
                "Cloud"
            ],
            "answer": "Cloud",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 343,
            "question": "The great wall of China commenced construction over 2000 years ago, what distance was it at its peak?",
            "options": [
                "6,500 miles",
                "4,500 miles",
                "3,500 miles",
                "5,500 miles"
            ],
            "answer": "5,500 miles",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 294,
            "question": "Who has won the most English FA Cups?",
            "options": [
                "Everton",
                "Arsenal",
                "Liverpool",
                "Man Utd"
            ],
            "answer": "Man Utd",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 72,
            "question": "Entomology is the science that studies",
            "options": [
                "The formation of rocks",
                "The origin and history of technical and scientific terms",
                "Behavior of human beings",
                "Insects"
            ],
            "answer": "Insects",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 417,
            "question": "Without justice ______ is weak.",
            "options": [
                "Society",
                "Courage",
                "Law",
                "Crime"
            ],
            "answer": "Courage",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 346,
            "question": "How many language India has officially?<br/>",
            "options": [
                "1",
                "2",
                "11",
                "22"
            ],
            "answer": "22",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 179,
            "question": "What happened that caused Romeo to fail to receive the letter notifying him about the friar's plan involving the potion?",
            "options": [
                "The person he sent to deliver the message couldn't find Romeo",
                "An outbreak of plague",
                "He never sent a letter",
                "The person he sent to deliver the message got lost"
            ],
            "answer": "An outbreak of plague",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 176,
            "question": "Who first recognizes Romeo at the Capulet party?",
            "options": [
                "Tybalt",
                "Juliet",
                "Paris",
                "Lady Capulet"
            ],
            "answer": "Tybalt",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 19,
            "question": "The title of which Pink Floyd album is also a chapter in 'The Wind In The Willows'?",
            "options": [
                "Wish you were here",
                "The piper at the gates of dawn",
                "Meddle",
                "Animals"
            ],
            "answer": "The piper at the gates of dawn",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 325,
            "question": "What is not allowed in speed walking",
            "options": [
                "To old your legs ",
                "Make a step that is smaller then 1 meter ",
                "Have your 2 legs at the same time of the ground ",
                "Walking slower then 10km/h "
            ],
            "answer": "Have your 2 legs at the same time of the ground ",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 206,
            "question": "\"Once more unto the breach dear friends, once more!\" This line is from the final play of a historical tetralogy by Shakespeare. Name the play.",
            "options": [
                "\"Julius Caesar\" ",
                "\"Hamlet\" ",
                "\"King Henry V\"",
                "\"Macbeth\" "
            ],
            "answer": "\"King Henry V\"",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 186,
            "question": "This author was born in India. One of his most famous books is a collection of short stories called \"The Jungle Book.\" The book's well-known characters include young Mowgli, who was raised in the Indian jungle by wolves, and Rikki-Tikki-Tavi, a brave mongoose. Who wrote \"The Jungle Book\"?",
            "options": [
                "Joseph Conrad",
                "Rudyard Kipling",
                "Herman Melville",
                "Jack London"
            ],
            "answer": "Rudyard Kipling",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 104,
            "question": "In Rudyard Kipling's \"Puck of Pook's Hill\", Puck introduces Dan and Una to various people who have passed through that part of England at times in the past. Whose story do they NOT hear? ",
            "options": [
                "A Roman centurion",
                "A pirate",
                "A Norman knight",
                "An ancient god"
            ],
            "answer": "A pirate",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 476,
            "question": "Virgin goddess of the hearth, home and cooking.",
            "options": [
                "Hermes",
                "Pluto/Hades",
                "Hestia",
                "Artemis"
            ],
            "answer": "Hestia",
            "category_id": 10
        },
        {
            "id": 55,
            "question": "What did Alfred Nobel develop?",
            "options": [
                "Atomic bomb",
                "Dynamite",
                "Nobelium",
                "Gunpowder "
            ],
            "answer": "Dynamite",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 342,
            "question": "Christ The Redeemer statue (130 feet tall) is located in which city?",
            "options": [
                "Buenos Aires",
                "Bras\u00edlia",
                "S\u00e3o Paulo",
                "Rio de Janeiro"
            ],
            "answer": "Rio de Janeiro",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 452,
            "question": "\u201cChoose a job you love, and you will never have to work a day in your life\u201d ",
            "options": [
                "Aristotle",
                "Confucius",
                "Socrates ",
                "Lao Tzu"
            ],
            "answer": "Confucius",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 160,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Grapes of Wrath\"?",
            "options": [
                "Richard Bach",
                "John Steinbeck",
                "Don Miguel Ruiz",
                "Dorothy Allison"
            ],
            "answer": "John Steinbeck",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 336,
            "question": "What is the name of this the most remote inhabited island in the world with its closest neighbour a distance of almost 1300 miles?",
            "options": [
                "Halloween Island",
                "Christmas Island",
                "New Years Island",
                "Easter Island"
            ],
            "answer": "Easter Island",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 197,
            "question": "Who said \"I Wandered Lonely as a Cloud\"",
            "options": [
                "William Wordsworth",
                "Julia Ward Howe",
                "William Ernest Henley",
                "William Shakespeare"
            ],
            "answer": "William Wordsworth",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 64,
            "question": "What was the first successful vaccine developed in history?",
            "options": [
                "Scarlet Fever",
                "Rabies",
                "Cholera",
                "Smallpox "
            ],
            "answer": "Smallpox ",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 387,
            "question": "What year was the last Roman Emperor Constantine XI defeated?",
            "options": [
                "453 AD",
                "1453 AD",
                "440 AD",
                "390 AD"
            ],
            "answer": "1453 AD",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 243,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Bramall Lane?",
            "options": [
                "Norwich",
                "Sheffield Wednesday",
                "Man Utd",
                "Sheffield United"
            ],
            "answer": "Sheffield United",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 216,
            "question": "The periodic symbol for Mercury is",
            "options": [
                "NaCl",
                "K`",
                "Hg",
                "Fe"
            ],
            "answer": "Hg",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 218,
            "question": "What is an Ion?",
            "options": [
                "A substance that is mined from the ground. ",
                "An atom with both a Neuron and an Electron. ",
                "An electrically charged Atom",
                "An atom that has been split"
            ],
            "answer": "An electrically charged Atom",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 45,
            "question": "Which actress plays a major role on the TV show 'The Big Bang Theory'?",
            "options": [
                "Emily Deschanel",
                "Sofia Vergara",
                "Kaley Cuoco",
                "Portia de Rossi "
            ],
            "answer": "Kaley Cuoco",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 42,
            "question": "What is the largest planet in our Solar System?",
            "options": [
                "Jupiter",
                "Pluto",
                "Saturn",
                "Earth "
            ],
            "answer": "Jupiter",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 262,
            "question": "When was the first world cup held?",
            "options": [
                "2003",
                "1981",
                "1989",
                "1985"
            ],
            "answer": "1989",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 280,
            "question": "Which boxer is the odd one out ?",
            "options": [
                "Joe Calzaghe",
                "James Toney",
                "Roy Jones",
                "Bernard Hopkins"
            ],
            "answer": "Bernard Hopkins",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 227,
            "question": "Which of the following is the largest organelle in eukaryotic cells? ",
            "options": [
                "Golgi apparatus ",
                "Nucleus",
                "Lysosome ",
                "ER"
            ],
            "answer": "Nucleus",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 185,
            "question": "What were Mercutio's last words?",
            "options": [
                "\"Two households, both alike in dignity, in fair Verona, where we lay our scene, from ancient grudge break to new mutiny, where civil blood makes civil hands unclean.\"",
                "\"For never was a story of more woe than this of Juliet and her Romeo.\"",
                "\"Help me into some houses, Benvolio, or I shall faint. A plague on both your houses! They have made worms' meat of me. I have it, and soundly too. Your houses!",
                "\"O, find him! Give this ring to my true knight and bid him come to take his last farewell.\""
            ],
            "answer": "\"Help me into some houses, Benvolio, or I shall faint. A plague on both your houses! They have made worms' meat of me. I have it, and soundly too. Your houses!",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 282,
            "question": "Who did Ray Leonard defeat to win his first world title ?",
            "options": [
                "Dave Green",
                "Thomas Hearns",
                "Floyd Mayweather Sr",
                "Wilfred Benitez"
            ],
            "answer": "Wilfred Benitez",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 41,
            "question": "Which country hosted the Summer Olympics in 2016?",
            "options": [
                "China",
                "Brazil",
                "Spain",
                "Greece "
            ],
            "answer": "Brazil",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 44,
            "question": "Which movie was the first to win 11 Academy Awards?",
            "options": [
                "Titanic",
                "Ben-Hur",
                "Sound of Music",
                "LOTR: Return of the King "
            ],
            "answer": "Ben-Hur",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 449,
            "question": "\"False words are not only evil in themselves, but they infect the soul with evil\"",
            "options": [
                "Lao Tzu",
                "Socrates ",
                "Confucius",
                "Aristotle"
            ],
            "answer": "Socrates ",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 217,
            "question": "What is an Element?",
            "options": [
                "A substance that can split into 2 different substances",
                "A pure substance that is maluable",
                "A pure substance that is in it simplest form. (can be broken down)",
                "A substance that isn't in it's purest form. (can be broken down)"
            ],
            "answer": "A pure substance that is in it simplest form. (can be broken down)",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 479,
            "question": "Virgin goddess of the hunt, wilderness, animals, childbirth and plague.",
            "options": [
                "Apollo",
                "Athena",
                "Ares",
                "Artemis"
            ],
            "answer": "Artemis",
            "category_id": 10
        },
        {
            "id": 425,
            "question": "Stick in the ______.",
            "options": [
                "Pubbing",
                "Suds",
                "Mud",
                "Pie"
            ],
            "answer": "Mud",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 474,
            "question": "The goddess of love, beauty, and desire.",
            "options": [
                "Apollo",
                "Zeus",
                "Athena",
                "Aphrodite"
            ],
            "answer": "Aphrodite",
            "category_id": 10
        },
        {
            "id": 290,
            "question": "What year did England win the World Cup?",
            "options": [
                "1970",
                "1956",
                "1966",
                "1984"
            ],
            "answer": "1966",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 58,
            "question": "Which mammal first reached Earth's orbit alive?",
            "options": [
                "Monkey",
                "Dog",
                "Cat",
                "Human "
            ],
            "answer": "Dog",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 146,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Catcher in the Rye\"?",
            "options": [
                "James Redfield",
                "J D Salinger",
                "James Baldwin",
                "Don Miguel Ruiz"
            ],
            "answer": "J D Salinger",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 308,
            "question": "Who knocked out Joe Louis in Madison Square Garden 1951?",
            "options": [
                "Max Schmeling",
                "Ezzard Charles",
                "Rocky Marciano",
                "Johnny Shkor"
            ],
            "answer": "Rocky Marciano",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3,
            "question": "Who wrote \"don't count your chickens before they are hatched\"?",
            "options": [
                "Aesop",
                "Shakespeare",
                "Ben  Franklin",
                "Chaucer"
            ],
            "answer": "Aesop",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 111,
            "question": "In the book, \"Bedknobs and Broomsticks\", Miss Price is studying to become ... ?",
            "options": [
                "A carpenter",
                "A witch",
                "A vampire slayer",
                "An astronaut"
            ],
            "answer": "A witch",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 13,
            "question": "A 'Miller' is a move in which sport?",
            "options": [
                "Ice Hockey",
                "Trampolining",
                "Diving",
                "Chess"
            ],
            "answer": "Trampolining",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 199,
            "question": "Who said \"Once upon a midnight dreary, while I pondered weak and weary\"",
            "options": [
                "William Shakespeare",
                "Alfred Lord Tennyson",
                "Robert Frost",
                "Edgar Allan Poe"
            ],
            "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 315,
            "question": "Who Has Served as Ryder Cup Captain Most Times?",
            "options": [
                "Jack Nicklaus",
                "Colin Montgomery",
                "Dai Reese",
                "Walter Hagen"
            ],
            "answer": "Walter Hagen",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 1,
            "question": "Where did The Flowerpot Men want to go in 1967?",
            "options": [
                "New York",
                "San Francisco",
                "Woodstock",
                "Memphis"
            ],
            "answer": "San Francisco",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 448,
            "question": "\"Being deeply loved by someone gives you strength, while loving someone deeply gives you courage\"",
            "options": [
                "Socrates ",
                "Aristotle",
                "Confucius",
                "Lao Tzu"
            ],
            "answer": "Lao Tzu",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 363,
            "question": "Which are true about the death of Princess Diana?",
            "options": [
                "A.  it was the result of injuries in a car crash in Pont de l'Alma road tunnel in Paris",
                "B.  it was caused by lightning",
                "C. Henri Paul was drunk, so investigations say it's his fault",
                "E. Diana was with Henri Paul and Dodi Fayed"
            ],
            "answer": "E. Diana was with Henri Paul and Dodi Fayed",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 240,
            "question": "Who's home ground is The New Den?",
            "options": [
                "Middlesbrough",
                "Arsenal",
                "Man Utd",
                "Millwall"
            ],
            "answer": "Millwall",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 226,
            "question": "What is the typical width of the lipid bilayer? ",
            "options": [
                "3 nanometers",
                "7 nanometers",
                "9 nanometers",
                "5 nanometers"
            ],
            "answer": "5 nanometers",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 366,
            "question": "Which are true about Romulus and Remus?",
            "options": [
                "A. they were suckled by a she-wolf",
                "B. they were twins",
                "C. they were sons of Rhea Silvia, daughter of Numitor, king of Alba Longa",
                "D. their grandfather was the legendary founder of Rome and the Roman Kingdom"
            ],
            "answer": "D. their grandfather was the legendary founder of Rome and the Roman Kingdom",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 340,
            "question": "Petra constructed around 6 century BC is famous for its rock cut architecture and water conduits system, where is it located?",
            "options": [
                "Egypt",
                "Iran",
                "Syria",
                "Jordan"
            ],
            "answer": "Jordan",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 207,
            "question": "\"It is a tale told by an idiot, full of sound and fury, signifying nothing.\" This is the end of a famous speech by the protagonist of Shakespeare's shortest tragedy, often compared to a morality play because of its references to moral issues such as power",
            "options": [
                "\"A Comedy of Errors\"",
                "\"Richard III\" ",
                "\"Macbeth\" ",
                "\"All's Well That Ends Well\" "
            ],
            "answer": "\"Macbeth\" ",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 75,
            "question": "Hitler party which came into power in 1933 is known as",
            "options": [
                "Democratic Party",
                "Nazi Party",
                "Labour Party",
                "Ku-Klux-Klan"
            ],
            "answer": "Nazi Party",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 347,
            "question": "Countries not speaking Spanish in Latin America?<br/>",
            "options": [
                "Brazil",
                "Argentina",
                "Panama",
                "Venezuela"
            ],
            "answer": "Brazil",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 36,
            "question": "Which band was not from Liverpool?",
            "options": [
                "Searchers",
                "A Flock of Seagulls",
                "Stone the crows",
                "OMD"
            ],
            "answer": "Stone the crows",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 119,
            "question": "How does Boxer die?",
            "options": [
                "A cart fell on him and crushed his lungs",
                "He dies in one of the fights between the men and the animals ",
                "He was shot",
                "The knackers"
            ],
            "answer": "The knackers",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 295,
            "question": "Who has won the most World Cups?",
            "options": [
                "Ireland",
                "England",
                "Argentina ",
                "Brazil"
            ],
            "answer": "Brazil",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 76,
            "question": "For which of the following disciplines is Nobel Prize awarded?",
            "options": [
                "All of the above",
                "Physics and Chemistry",
                "Physiology or Medicine",
                "Literature, Peace and Economics"
            ],
            "answer": "All of the above",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 73,
            "question": "First China War was fought between",
            "options": [
                "China and France",
                "China and Spain",
                "China and Portugal",
                "China and Britain"
            ],
            "answer": "China and Britain",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 380,
            "question": "Legends which are products of the Frontier Myth",
            "options": [
                "A. Wild Bill",
                "B. Calamity Jane",
                "C. Jesse James' gang",
                "E. Buffalo Bill"
            ],
            "answer": "E. Buffalo Bill",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 353,
            "question": "Which of these are said about Elvis Presley?people say he's alive; supposedly been seen various times in various places<br style=\"color: rgb(45, 54, 57);\"/><br/>",
            "options": [
                "A. he's alive & been seen various times in various places",
                "B. the Presley's Commission had an in-depth analysis of Elvis' death, which was only a death-hoax propaganda",
                "C. they spelled his name on his gravestone as Aron rather than Aaron (sinister implications)",
                "E.he was part of a group called \"The Fraternity\" which involved criminal schemes"
            ],
            "answer": "E.he was part of a group called \"The Fraternity\" which involved criminal schemes",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 59,
            "question": "What funk/soul band was Lionel Richie a member of?",
            "options": [
                "Commodores",
                "Amigas",
                "Spectrums",
                "Ataris "
            ],
            "answer": "Commodores",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 238,
            "question": "Who's home ground is St James' Park?",
            "options": [
                "Tottenham Hotspur",
                "Sheffield Wednesday",
                "Millwall",
                "Newcastle United"
            ],
            "answer": "Newcastle United",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 258,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Elland Road?",
            "options": [
                "Norwich",
                "Sunderland",
                "Millwall",
                "Leeds United"
            ],
            "answer": "Leeds United",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 389,
            "question": "What year did Hadrian's Wall (a defensive fortification in Roman Britain) began construction?",
            "options": [
                "102 AD",
                "112 AD",
                "122 AD",
                "132 AD"
            ],
            "answer": "122 AD",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 339,
            "question": "Who built these pyramids?",
            "options": [
                "Egyptians",
                "Greeks",
                "Aztecs",
                "Romans"
            ],
            "answer": "Egyptians",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 327,
            "question": "What is the distance between the hurdles at 400m hurdles for men? ",
            "options": [
                "55 meters",
                "15 meters",
                "25 meters",
                "35 meters"
            ],
            "answer": "35 meters",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 222,
            "question": "An example of an Element is?",
            "options": [
                "Oxygen ",
                "Water ",
                "Hydrogen",
                "Carbon"
            ],
            "answer": "Hydrogen",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 267,
            "question": "Which boxer has the  most consecutive successful title defenses ?",
            "options": [
                "Julio Cesar Chavez",
                "Roy Jones",
                "Archie Moore",
                "Joe Louis"
            ],
            "answer": "Joe Louis",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 172,
            "question": "What do Lord Montague and Lord Capulet agree to do at the end of the play?",
            "options": [
                "They never stop fighting",
                "They don't agree on anything",
                "They seek for more revenge",
                "Stop the feuding and build gold statues"
            ],
            "answer": "Stop the feuding and build gold statues",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 310,
            "question": "The Rumble in the Jungle was a historic boxing event that took place on October 30, 1974 between ????",
            "options": [
                "Sugar Ray Robinson",
                "Muhammad Ali",
                "Jake LaMotta",
                "George Foreman"
            ],
            "answer": "George Foreman",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 134,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Happy Hooker: Her Own Story\"?",
            "options": [
                "Xaviera Hollander",
                "Dr Benjamin Spock",
                "Charles Dickens",
                "Nathanael West"
            ],
            "answer": "Xaviera Hollander",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 167,
            "question": "Who is lying next to Juliet in the tomb?",
            "options": [
                "Lord Capulet",
                "The Nurse",
                "Lady Capulet",
                "Tybalt"
            ],
            "answer": "Tybalt",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 80,
            "question": "Golf player Vijay Singh belongs to which country?",
            "options": [
                "UK",
                "Thailand",
                "USA",
                "Fiji"
            ],
            "answer": "Fiji",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 246,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Riverside Stadium?",
            "options": [
                "Millwall",
                "Tottenham Hotspur",
                "Arsenal",
                "Middlesbrough"
            ],
            "answer": "Middlesbrough",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 117,
            "question": "Who was accused of destroying the windmill?",
            "options": [
                "Napoleon",
                "Snowball",
                "Mr.Jones ",
                "Old Major"
            ],
            "answer": "Snowball",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 372,
            "question": "Which of these are components of the hero's journey?",
            "options": [
                "A. he finds the courage to pursue the path",
                "B. the hero struggles to overcome his fear and other obstacles to reach his goal",
                "C. he rescues a damsel in distress",
                "D. his experiences lead to the realization of his own potential"
            ],
            "answer": "D. his experiences lead to the realization of his own potential",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 37,
            "question": "Which boxer twice defeated Nigel Benn in 1996?",
            "options": [
                "Thulani Malinga",
                "Steve Collins",
                "Roy Jones",
                "Gerald McClellan"
            ],
            "answer": "Steve Collins",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 184,
            "question": "Finish the quote: \"For never was a story of more woe than this of...\"",
            "options": [
                "Romeo and Benvolio",
                "Capulet and Montague",
                "Juliet and Paris",
                "Juliet and her Romeo"
            ],
            "answer": "Juliet and her Romeo",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 275,
            "question": "Who did Erik Morales defeat to become world champion for the first time ?",
            "options": [
                "Kevin Kelley",
                "Wayne McCullough",
                "Marco Antonio Barrera",
                "Daniel Zaragoza"
            ],
            "answer": "Daniel Zaragoza",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 71,
            "question": "Grand Central Terminal, Park Avenue, New York is the world's",
            "options": [
                "None of the above",
                "Longest railway station",
                "Highest railway station",
                "Largest railway station"
            ],
            "answer": "Largest railway station",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 283,
            "question": "Which boxer did not defeat Shane Mosley ?",
            "options": [
                "Vernon Forrest",
                "Ronald Wright",
                "Miguel Cotto",
                "Oscar Dela Hoya"
            ],
            "answer": "Oscar Dela Hoya",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 416,
            "question": "A stitch in time saves ______.",
            "options": [
                "Lives",
                "Time",
                "Nine",
                "Wives"
            ],
            "answer": "Nine",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 279,
            "question": "'The Matrix' is the alias for which boxer ?",
            "options": [
                "Danny Green",
                "Andre Ward",
                "Glen Johnson",
                "Andre Dirrell"
            ],
            "answer": "Andre Dirrell",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 6,
            "question": "In which film do the words \"I love you\" save the planet earth?",
            "options": [
                "The Day After Tomorrow",
                "The 5th Element",
                "Mars Attacks",
                "Independence Day"
            ],
            "answer": "The 5th Element",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 323,
            "question": "In which sport do you have to use a gun?",
            "options": [
                "Hankumdo ",
                "Paragliding ",
                "Javelin fish ",
                "Biatlon "
            ],
            "answer": "Biatlon ",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 61,
            "question": "Which US President is most to the left on the Mount Rushmore National Memorial?",
            "options": [
                "George Washington",
                "Thomas Jefferson",
                "Theodore Roosevelt",
                "Abraham Lincoln "
            ],
            "answer": "George Washington",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 395,
            "question": "What was the Buddha's first name?",
            "options": [
                "Gadhadhar",
                "Gautama",
                "Gajanan",
                "Gajananvihari"
            ],
            "answer": "Gautama",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 14,
            "question": "Festfolk was the original name for which group?",
            "options": [
                "The Beach Boys",
                "ABBA",
                "Motorhead",
                "Simon and Garfunkel"
            ],
            "answer": "ABBA",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 373,
            "question": "Which are true about the cosmic egg?",
            "options": [
                "A. it's a mythological motif found in the creation myths of many cultures and civilizations.",
                "B. it is celebrated at Easter",
                "C.  typically, a beginning of some sory",
                "E. the universe or some primordial being comes into existence by \"hatching\""
            ],
            "answer": "E. the universe or some primordial being comes into existence by \"hatching\"",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 470,
            "question": "\"The first thing which I can record concerning myself is, that I was born. These are wonderful words. This life, to which neither time nor eternity can bring diminution - this everlasting living soul, began. My mind loses itself in these depths\". Which world famous person made this unexpected remark?",
            "options": [
                "Mother Theresa",
                "Groucho Marx",
                "John F. Kennedy",
                "Donald Trump"
            ],
            "answer": "Groucho Marx",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 303,
            "question": "Which boxer is quoted to have saying \"float like a butterfly, sting like a bee\"?",
            "options": [
                "Sugar Ray Robinson",
                "Joe Louis",
                "Jack Johnson",
                "Muhammad Ali"
            ],
            "answer": "Muhammad Ali",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 411,
            "question": "______ the mustard.",
            "options": [
                "Spread",
                "Eat",
                "Share",
                "Cut"
            ],
            "answer": "Cut",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 241,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Carrow Road?",
            "options": [
                "Arsenal",
                "Man Utd",
                "Man City",
                "Norwich"
            ],
            "answer": "Norwich",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 11,
            "question": "What does a nidoligist study?",
            "options": [
                "Waves",
                "Clouds",
                "Bird Nests",
                "Caves"
            ],
            "answer": "Bird Nests",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 182,
            "question": "Where in Italy is \"Romeo and Juliet\" set?",
            "options": [
                "Rome",
                "Verona",
                "Florence",
                "Milan"
            ],
            "answer": "Verona",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 24,
            "question": "Off the coast of which country did the Amoco Cadiz sink?",
            "options": [
                "South Africa",
                "France",
                "USA",
                "Spain"
            ],
            "answer": "France",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 165,
            "question": "Who wrote \"Fear of Flying\"?",
            "options": [
                "Edward Ball",
                "Nicholas Evans",
                "Erica Jong",
                "Richard Bach"
            ],
            "answer": "Erica Jong",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 314,
            "question": "How many majors has Jack Nicklaus won?",
            "options": [
                "12",
                "15",
                "18",
                "20"
            ],
            "answer": "18",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 53,
            "question": "Other than eggs, what is a primary ingredient in Eggs Florentine?",
            "options": [
                "Ham",
                "Avocado",
                "Spinach",
                "Gorgonzola "
            ],
            "answer": "Spinach",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 23,
            "question": "Speed skating originated in which country?",
            "options": [
                "Russia",
                "Netherlands",
                "Canada",
                "Norway"
            ],
            "answer": "Netherlands",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 203,
            "question": "Who said \"Out of the night that covers me, Black as the pit from pole to pole\"",
            "options": [
                "William Wordsworth",
                "William Ernest Henley",
                "Joyce Kilmer",
                "Julia Ward Howe"
            ],
            "answer": "William Ernest Henley",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 27,
            "question": "In which year did Louis Reard invent the bikini?",
            "options": [
                "1906",
                "1926",
                "1946",
                "1966"
            ],
            "answer": "1946",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 124,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Pearl\"?",
            "options": [
                "Eckhart Tolle",
                "Henry James",
                "Eckhart Tolle",
                "John Steinbeck"
            ],
            "answer": "John Steinbeck",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 405,
            "question": "That's the ______ that broke the camels back.",
            "options": [
                "Stone",
                "Sweet",
                "Straw",
                "Stick"
            ],
            "answer": "Straw",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 345,
            "question": "What is capital city of Australia?<br/>",
            "options": [
                "Sydney",
                "Melbourne",
                "Canberra",
                "Perth"
            ],
            "answer": "Canberra",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 63,
            "question": "Adele performed the theme song to which James Bond film?",
            "options": [
                "Casino Royale",
                "Quantum of Solace",
                "Skyfall",
                "From Russia With Love "
            ],
            "answer": "Skyfall",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 129,
            "question": "Who wrote \"A Tale of Two Cities\"?",
            "options": [
                "Eckhart Tolle",
                "Alice Walker",
                "Joseph Heller",
                "Charles Dickens"
            ],
            "answer": "Charles Dickens",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 120,
            "question": "How does Napoleon show his discontent with Snowball's ideas for the windmill?",
            "options": [
                "He pees on the plans.",
                "He tears up the plans ",
                "He crudely insults Snowball.",
                "He explains why it is a bad idea."
            ],
            "answer": "He pees on the plans.",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 77,
            "question": "Galileo was an Italian astronomer who",
            "options": [
                "All of the above",
                "Developed the telescope",
                "Discovered that the movement of pendulum produces a regular time measurement",
                "Discovered four satellites of Jupiter"
            ],
            "answer": "All of the above",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 251,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Stadium of Light?",
            "options": [
                "Chelsea",
                "Middlesbrough",
                "Man City",
                "Sunderland"
            ],
            "answer": "Sunderland",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 378,
            "question": "Which are true about Rainbow Nation?<a class=\"SetPageTerm-definitionText\" style=\"color: rgb(45, 54, 57);\"><span class=\"TermText notranslate lang-en qDef\"><br/><br/></span></a>",
            "options": [
                "It was a term coined by Archbishop Desmond Tutu",
                "Refers to post-apartheid South Africa, after South Africa's first fully democratic election in 1994",
                "It was rejected by Nelson Mandela",
                "South African flag symbolises it, with its 6 colors"
            ],
            "answer": "South African flag symbolises it, with its 6 colors",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 126,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Empty Raincoat\"?",
            "options": [
                "Charles Handy",
                "James Redfield",
                "Paul Bowles",
                "Charles Dickens"
            ],
            "answer": "Charles Handy",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 92,
            "question": "Pigs cant fly, but which one of these CAN they do?",
            "options": [
                "Stand on their two back legs with there front ones in the air for up to 48 minutes",
                "Run 30 Mph",
                "Grow a 3rd ear in the Winter",
                "Swim"
            ],
            "answer": "Swim",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 252,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Loftus Road?",
            "options": [
                "Everton",
                "West Ham United",
                "Millwall",
                "QPR"
            ],
            "answer": "QPR",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 159,
            "question": "Who wrote \"Six Thinking Hats\"?",
            "options": [
                "James Redfield",
                "Nathanael West",
                "Willa Cather",
                "Edward de Bono"
            ],
            "answer": "Edward de Bono",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 264,
            "question": "Which of these teams have not won the world cup?",
            "options": [
                "New Zealand",
                "Ireland",
                "Australia",
                "France"
            ],
            "answer": "France",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 204,
            "question": "Who said \"Love one another, but make not a bond of love: Let it rather be a moving sea between the shores of your souls.\"",
            "options": [
                "William Shakespeare",
                "Joyce Kilmer",
                "Khalil Gibran",
                "William Wordsworth"
            ],
            "answer": "Khalil Gibran",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 459,
            "question": "\"one small step for man, one giant leap for mankind\"",
            "options": [
                "Leonardo da Vinci",
                "President Truman",
                "Neil Armstrong",
                "John F. Kennedy"
            ],
            "answer": "Neil Armstrong",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 355,
            "question": "Country A's economy has been faltering for the past 2 administrations. As economic adviser of the new administration, what factors would you have to look at to solve the problem?",
            "options": [
                "A. the country's monetary and fiscal policy",
                "B. the state of the global economy & exchange rates",
                "C. unemployment levels  and productivity",
                "E. inflation"
            ],
            "answer": "E. inflation",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 388,
            "question": "Which Roman Empire was the 1st Roman emperor to convert to Christianity? ",
            "options": [
                "Julian",
                "Caracalla",
                "Commodus",
                "Constantine"
            ],
            "answer": "Constantine",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 21,
            "question": "Which pop duo was the first western band to play in The Peoples Republic of China?",
            "options": [
                "Wham",
                "Simon and Garfunkel",
                "Chas and Dave",
                "Right Said Fred"
            ],
            "answer": "Wham",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 250,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Boleyn Ground?",
            "options": [
                "Millwall",
                "Charlton Athletic",
                "Bolton Wanderers",
                "West Ham United"
            ],
            "answer": "West Ham United",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 239,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Etihad Stadium?",
            "options": [
                "Sheffield Wednesday",
                "QPR",
                "Sheffield Wednesday",
                "Man City"
            ],
            "answer": "Man City",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 326,
            "question": "What is the maximum number of points that can be scored in a bowling game (a perfect game)?",
            "options": [
                "250",
                "200",
                "360",
                "300"
            ],
            "answer": "300",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 169,
            "question": "She uses a gun",
            "options": [
                "She uses a gun",
                "She uses a \"happy dagger\"",
                "She doesn't die",
                "She uses leftover poison"
            ],
            "answer": "She uses a \"happy dagger\"",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 189,
            "question": "This story was written by the English writer Charles Dickens. A grumpy old miser named Ebenezer Scrooge is transformed into a generous and kind person after being visited by three ghosts who show him the error of his ways. What is the book's title?",
            "options": [
                "A Christmas Eve Visit",
                "Marley and Scrooge",
                "Three Christmas Ghosts",
                "A Christmas Carol"
            ],
            "answer": "A Christmas Carol",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 424,
            "question": "A little ______ is a dangerous thing.",
            "options": [
                "Mind",
                "Car",
                "Knowledge",
                "Money"
            ],
            "answer": "Knowledge",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 375,
            "question": "The traits of conspiracy theorists include",
            "options": [
                "A. they feel a lack of control over their lives",
                "B. they experience mental health issues",
                "C. they are evidence-based researchers",
                "E. they are narcissistic"
            ],
            "answer": "E. they are narcissistic",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 309,
            "question": "Who was the first person to defeat Mike Tyson?",
            "options": [
                "Frank Bruno",
                "Evander Holyfield",
                " Lennox Lewis",
                "James \"Buster\" Douglas"
            ],
            "answer": "James \"Buster\" Douglas",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 313,
            "question": "What age was Rory McIlroy when he won hes first major?",
            "options": [
                "21",
                "20",
                "23",
                "22"
            ],
            "answer": "22",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 364,
            "question": "What are true about Martina Navratilova",
            "options": [
                "Prague, Czechoslovakia",
                "Her career has spanned 5 decades",
                "She is also a professional basketball player",
                "She was the best tennis player in the world for  332 weeks for singles, and 237 weeks for doubles"
            ],
            "answer": "She was the best tennis player in the world for  332 weeks for singles, and 237 weeks for doubles",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 25,
            "question": "The song 'An Englishman in New York' was about which man?",
            "options": [
                "Quentin Crisp",
                "Sting",
                "John Lennon",
                "Gordon Sumner"
            ],
            "answer": "Quentin Crisp",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 312,
            "question": "As at 2010 how many majors has Tiger Woods won?",
            "options": [
                "14",
                "10",
                "12",
                "16"
            ],
            "answer": "14",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 196,
            "question": "Who said \"I took the one less traveled by, And that has made all the difference.\"",
            "options": [
                "William Wordsworth",
                "Khalil Gibran",
                "Robert Frost",
                "Joyce Kilmer"
            ],
            "answer": "Robert Frost",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 8,
            "question": "In which book is there an inn called Admiral Benbow?",
            "options": [
                "Lord of the Rings",
                "Gulliver's Travels",
                "Treasure Island",
                "Peter Pan"
            ],
            "answer": "Treasure Island",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 220,
            "question": "The periodic symbol for Potassium is?",
            "options": [
                "K",
                "Hg",
                "Fe",
                "NaCl"
            ],
            "answer": "K",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 430,
            "question": "A closed ______ catches no flies.",
            "options": [
                "Sack",
                "Mouth",
                "Fist",
                "Trap"
            ],
            "answer": "Mouth",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 236,
            "question": "What organelle is responsible for carrying out photosynthesis? ",
            "options": [
                "Vacuole ",
                "Mitochondria ",
                "Nucleus ",
                "Chloroplasts "
            ],
            "answer": "Chloroplasts ",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 356,
            "question": "According to Jesse Walker, along with benevolent conspiracies, there is also...",
            "options": [
                "A. the enemy outside",
                "B. the  enemy within",
                "C. the enemy above",
                "D. the enemy below"
            ],
            "answer": "D. the enemy below",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 142,
            "question": "Who wrote \"Jaws\"?",
            "options": [
                "Joan Didion",
                "J D Salinger",
                "Eckhart Tolle",
                "Peter Benchley"
            ],
            "answer": "Peter Benchley",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 81,
            "question": "What is the Least played game",
            "options": [
                "Dora the Explora XD",
                "CS GO",
                "Fifa",
                "Monopoly"
            ],
            "answer": "CS GO",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 255,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Reebok Stadium?",
            "options": [
                "Charlton Athletic",
                "Millwall",
                "Middlesbrough",
                "Bolton Wanderers"
            ],
            "answer": "Bolton Wanderers",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 181,
            "question": "Who does Juliet marry?",
            "options": [
                "Mercutio",
                "Paris",
                "Tybalt",
                "Romeo"
            ],
            "answer": "Romeo",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 307,
            "question": "Walker Smith Jr., May 3, 1921 \u2013 April 12, 1989 is better known as ?",
            "options": [
                "Joe Louis",
                "Sugar Ray Robinson",
                "Joe Frazier",
                "Sugar Ray Leonard"
            ],
            "answer": "Sugar Ray Robinson",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 367,
            "question": "Which are true about the Gunpowder Plot?",
            "options": [
                "A. Rich Catholics and the gentry helped the masterminds",
                "B. It was planned by Robert Catesby and Guy Fawkes",
                "C. It was more than just an assassination",
                "D. it came about to give Catholics a chance"
            ],
            "answer": "D. it came about to give Catholics a chance",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 382,
            "question": "Donald Trump was born in a hospital that also houses",
            "options": [
                "B. the Centre for Tropical Diseases",
                "C. the Pentagon",
                "D. Area 51 experiments",
                "A. the Brady Institute for Traumatic Brain Injury."
            ],
            "answer": "A. the Brady Institute for Traumatic Brain Injury.",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 69,
            "question": "What is the name of the boxer whose life story is depicted in the 1999 movie 'The Hurricane'?",
            "options": [
                "Muhammad Ali",
                "Jake LaMotta",
                "Rubin Carter",
                "Rocky Marciano "
            ],
            "answer": "Rubin Carter",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 391,
            "question": "What year was JFK assassinated?",
            "options": [
                "1966",
                "1963",
                "1965",
                "1964"
            ],
            "answer": "1963",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 125,
            "question": "Who wrote \"Think and Grow Rich\"?",
            "options": [
                "Richard Bach",
                "Nicholas Evans",
                "Richard Bach",
                "Napoleon Hill"
            ],
            "answer": "Napoleon Hill",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 208,
            "question": "\"Is it possible?--Confess,--handkerchief!--O devil!\" These words belong to the protagonist of which 1603 Shakespearean tragedy?",
            "options": [
                "\"Antony and Cleopatra\" ",
                "\"A Midsummer Night's Dream\" ",
                "\"Much Ado About Nothing\" ",
                "\"Othello\""
            ],
            "answer": "\"Othello\"",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 32,
            "question": "Doris Day had a sleepy hit with which song?",
            "options": [
                "Pillow talk",
                "Golden slumbers",
                "The beds too big without you",
                "Tears on my pillow"
            ],
            "answer": "Pillow talk",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 344,
            "question": "Which countries use french?<br/>",
            "options": [
                "Portugal",
                "Belgium",
                "Russia",
                "Netherland"
            ],
            "answer": "Belgium",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 183,
            "question": "What do Paris, Juliet, Romeo, Lady Montague, Mercutio, Tybalt have in common?",
            "options": [
                "They are all related",
                "They were the only ones who survived",
                "They all died",
                "They have nothing in common"
            ],
            "answer": "They all died",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 338,
            "question": "Where is Newgrange - a 5000 year old Passage Tomb located?",
            "options": [
                "France",
                "Spain",
                "Scotland",
                "Ireland"
            ],
            "answer": "Ireland",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 87,
            "question": "What was the First Mario game created?",
            "options": [
                "Mario 64",
                "Super Mario Bros Deluxe",
                "Donkey kong game thing?",
                "Mario Kart"
            ],
            "answer": "Donkey kong game thing?",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 132,
            "question": "Who wrote \"Nineteen Eighty-Four\"?",
            "options": [
                "George Orwell",
                "Dr Benjamin Spock",
                "Joseph Heller",
                "Edward Ball"
            ],
            "answer": "George Orwell",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 99,
            "question": "In Snooker what is the quickest time recorded for a 147 maximum break?",
            "options": [
                "6 Minutes 53 seconds",
                "5 Minutes 43 seconds",
                "5 Minutes 20 Seconds",
                "4 Minutes 54 seconds"
            ],
            "answer": "5 Minutes 20 Seconds",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 487,
            "question": "The queen of marriage, women, childbirth, heirs, kings and empires. ",
            "options": [
                "Hera",
                "Zeus",
                "Hestia",
                "Apollo"
            ],
            "answer": "Hera",
            "category_id": 10
        },
        {
            "id": 450,
            "question": "\"What we think, or what we know, or what we believe is, in the end, of little consequence. The only consequence is what we do.\"",
            "options": [
                "Marcel Proust",
                "Baltasar Gracian",
                "Abraham Lincoln",
                "John Ruskin"
            ],
            "answer": "John Ruskin",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 137,
            "question": "Who wrote \"Peace is Every Step\"?",
            "options": [
                "Charles Dickens",
                "Thich Nhat Hanh",
                "Richard Bach",
                "Nicholas Evans"
            ],
            "answer": "Thich Nhat Hanh",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 211,
            "question": "\"Take then thy bond, take thou thy pound of flesh.\" These words are uttered by a Shakespearean heroine in one of his most popular comedies, which has raised numerous questions related to anti-semitism.",
            "options": [
                "\"The Merchant of Venice\" ",
                "\"The Taming of the Shrew\" ",
                "\"Richard III\"",
                "\"Henry V\" "
            ],
            "answer": "\"The Merchant of Venice\" ",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 436,
            "question": "Do not use a ______ to remove a fly from your friend's forehead.",
            "options": [
                "Spoon",
                "Hatchet",
                "Balloon",
                "Ratchet"
            ],
            "answer": "Hatchet",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 143,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Common Sense Book of Baby and Child Care\"?",
            "options": [
                "George Orwell",
                "Dr Benjamin Spock",
                "Willa Cather",
                "Richard Bach"
            ],
            "answer": "Dr Benjamin Spock",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 86,
            "question": "What Game is the most Overplayed game ever?",
            "options": [
                "Or is it Diablo",
                "Is it Minecraft?",
                "Is it World of WarCraft?",
                "Is it Fifa 16/17?"
            ],
            "answer": "Is it World of WarCraft?",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 253,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Hillsborough?",
            "options": [
                "Chelsea",
                "Arsenal",
                "Crystal Palace",
                "Sheffield Wednesday"
            ],
            "answer": "Sheffield Wednesday",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 272,
            "question": "Which boxer had 'Black Mamba' as an alias ?",
            "options": [
                "Nigel Benn",
                "Aaron Pryor",
                "Jack Johnson",
                "Roger Mayweather"
            ],
            "answer": "Roger Mayweather",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 90,
            "question": "Where are the Nazca lines?",
            "options": [
                "Peru",
                "Spain",
                "Sweeden",
                "Germany"
            ],
            "answer": "Peru",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 400,
            "question": "That's the way the ball ______.",
            "options": [
                "Drops",
                "Bounces",
                "Rolls",
                "Falls"
            ],
            "answer": "Bounces",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 195,
            "question": "This French author wrote about space and undersea travel long before they were considered a real possibility, and has often been called \"the father of science fiction.\" His books include such daring adventures as \"A Journey to the Center of the Earth\", \"Twenty Thousand Leagues Under the Sea\" and \"Around the World in Eighty Days.\" Who was he?",
            "options": [
                "Jules Verne",
                "Verne Troyer",
                "Verne Gagne",
                "Jules Feiffer"
            ],
            "answer": "Jules Verne",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 414,
            "question": "______ can't be choosers.",
            "options": [
                "Posers",
                "Beggars",
                "Losers",
                "Children"
            ],
            "answer": "Beggars",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 455,
            "question": "\"Happiness depends upon ourselves\"",
            "options": [
                "Socrates ",
                "Confucius",
                "Aristotle",
                "Lao Tzu"
            ],
            "answer": "Aristotle",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 480,
            "question": "The god of wine, parties and festivals, madness, drunkenness and pleasure at forever young.",
            "options": [
                "Dionysus",
                "Dionysus",
                "Hephaestus",
                "Hera"
            ],
            "answer": "Dionysus",
            "category_id": 10
        },
        {
            "id": 439,
            "question": "Praise without profit puts little in the ______.",
            "options": [
                "Hand",
                "Wallet",
                "Pocket",
                "Pot"
            ],
            "answer": "Pot",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 96,
            "question": "Which of these is NOT a Capital City",
            "options": [
                "Istanbul ",
                "Wellington",
                "Berlin",
                "Ankara"
            ],
            "answer": "Istanbul ",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 415,
            "question": "You're making a ______ out of a molehill.",
            "options": [
                "Monster",
                "Milkshake",
                "Haystack",
                "Mountain"
            ],
            "answer": "Mountain",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 440,
            "question": "______ is a great story teller",
            "options": [
                "Time",
                "Mystery",
                "History",
                "A mime"
            ],
            "answer": "Time",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 369,
            "question": "Which of these are true about the July Plot?",
            "options": [
                "A. It was an an assassination attempt",
                "B. the target was Adolf Hitler",
                "C. it took place in Area 51",
                "E. it took place on July 20, 1944"
            ],
            "answer": "E. it took place on July 20, 1944",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 362,
            "question": "Which of these are &#34;facts&#34; put forth by conspiracy theorists about 9/11?",
            "options": [
                "Insider traders knew about the attacks before they happened",
                "Air defense was told to stand down (NORAD)",
                "When the Pentagon was attacked, the impact holes were smaller than American Airlines planes",
                "Black boxes found by the search crew were kept secret; these would be evidence into what happened inside the cockpits"
            ],
            "answer": "Black boxes found by the search crew were kept secret; these would be evidence into what happened inside the cockpits",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 408,
            "question": "She is such a fair-______ friend.",
            "options": [
                "Minded",
                "Haried",
                "Fighting",
                "Weathered"
            ],
            "answer": "Weathered",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 74,
            "question": "Gulf cooperation council was originally formed by",
            "options": [
                "Third World Nations",
                "Bahrain, Kuwait, Oman, Qatar, Saudi Arabia and United Arab Emirates",
                "Second World Nations",
                "Fourth World Nations"
            ],
            "answer": "Bahrain, Kuwait, Oman, Qatar, Saudi Arabia and United Arab Emirates",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 224,
            "question": "Which of the following is the main component of the cytoplasm?",
            "options": [
                "Cytosine",
                "Ectoderm",
                "Chlorophyll",
                "Cytosol"
            ],
            "answer": "Cytosol",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 248,
            "question": "Who's home ground is DW Stadium?",
            "options": [
                "Bolton Wanderers",
                "Everton",
                "Newcastle United",
                "Wigan Athletic"
            ],
            "answer": "Wigan Athletic",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 40,
            "question": "For how long is a dog pregnant?",
            "options": [
                "9 Weeks",
                "9 Days",
                "9 Months",
                "9 Fortnights"
            ],
            "answer": "9 Weeks",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 458,
            "question": "\u201cNot all of us can do great things. But we can do small things with great love\u201d",
            "options": [
                "Mahatma Gandhi",
                "Winston Churchill",
                "Jesus Christ ",
                "Mother Teresa"
            ],
            "answer": "Mother Teresa",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 445,
            "question": "Many ______ make light work.",
            "options": [
                "Hands",
                "Heads",
                "Fools",
                "Prayers"
            ],
            "answer": "Hands",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 101,
            "question": "In Roald Dahl's \"The Witches\", what do the witches want to turn children into?",
            "options": [
                "Mice",
                "Pumpkins",
                "Little witches",
                "Water"
            ],
            "answer": "Mice",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 161,
            "question": "Who wrote \"Emotional Intelligence\"?",
            "options": [
                "Paul Bowles",
                "Kenneth Grahame",
                "Erica Jong",
                "Daniel Goleman"
            ],
            "answer": "Daniel Goleman",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 330,
            "question": "The Great Barrier Reef is located in which continent? ",
            "options": [
                "Europe",
                "South America",
                "Asia",
                "Australia"
            ],
            "answer": "Australia",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 469,
            "question": "\"Forgiveness is the fragrance that the violet sheds on the heal (sic) that has crushed it.\" Which great American writer, forever linked to the Mississippi River, said this?",
            "options": [
                "Herman Melville",
                "William Faulkner",
                "Nathaniel Hawthorne",
                "Mark Twain"
            ],
            "answer": "Mark Twain",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 16,
            "question": "Fredrick Sanger invented which life saver?",
            "options": [
                "Insulin",
                "Safety Pin",
                "Inflatable Life Raft",
                "Aspirin"
            ],
            "answer": "Insulin",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 29,
            "question": "What are the names of the two main characters in Diana Gabaldon's highland saga novels?",
            "options": [
                "Jamie and Claire",
                "Fergus and Fiona",
                "Rab and Elizabeth",
                "Hamish and Maggie"
            ],
            "answer": "Jamie and Claire",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 485,
            "question": "The king of the Underworld and god of the dead and the hidden wealth of the Earth. ",
            "options": [
                "Zeus",
                "Hestia",
                "Pluto/Hades",
                "Aphrodite"
            ],
            "answer": "Pluto/Hades",
            "category_id": 10
        },
        {
            "id": 102,
            "question": "In this book, a boy with a scar on his face goes to Wizard School at Hogwarts. What is the boy's cousin's name?",
            "options": [
                "Dudley",
                "Draco",
                "Ron",
                "Piers"
            ],
            "answer": "Dudley",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 4,
            "question": "Which kind of animal did Florence Nightingale often carry around in her pocket?     ",
            "options": [
                "Kitten",
                "Puppy",
                "Owl",
                "Snake"
            ],
            "answer": "Owl",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 105,
            "question": "In this book, a young boy brings his toy Indian to life inside a magic cupboard. What is the boy's name?",
            "options": [
                "Patrick",
                "Omri",
                "Cyril",
                "Wart"
            ],
            "answer": "Omri",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 254,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Turf Moor?",
            "options": [
                "Crystal Palace",
                "Bolton Wanderers",
                "QPR",
                "Burnley"
            ],
            "answer": "Burnley",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 79,
            "question": "Exposure to sunlight helps a person improve his health because",
            "options": [
                "The pigment cells in the skin get stimulated and produce a healthy tan",
                "The infrared light kills bacteria in the body",
                "Resistance power increases",
                "The ultraviolet rays convert skin oil into Vitamin D"
            ],
            "answer": "The ultraviolet rays convert skin oil into Vitamin D",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 432,
            "question": "He who begins too much ______ little",
            "options": [
                "Mends",
                "Avoids",
                "Makes",
                "Accomplishes"
            ],
            "answer": "Accomplishes",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 18,
            "question": "Herodotus is known as the father of what?",
            "options": [
                "History",
                "Medicine",
                "Theatre",
                "Music"
            ],
            "answer": "History",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 406,
            "question": "Young men may ______ old men must.",
            "options": [
                "Die",
                "Fight",
                "Cry",
                "Try"
            ],
            "answer": "Die",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 276,
            "question": "Who referred to Julio Cesar Chavez as 'hail Cesar' ?",
            "options": [
                "Emanuel Steward",
                "Bob Sheridan",
                "Larry Merchant",
                "Don King"
            ],
            "answer": "Don King",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 130,
            "question": "Who wrote \"Motivation and Personality\"?",
            "options": [
                "Thomas Merton",
                "Nicholas Evans",
                "Maxine Hong",
                "Abraham Maslow"
            ],
            "answer": "Abraham Maslow",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 144,
            "question": "Who wrote \"Jonathan Livingstone Seagull\"?",
            "options": [
                "Erica Jong",
                "Eckhart Tolle",
                "Nathanael West",
                "Richard Bach"
            ],
            "answer": "Richard Bach",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 302,
            "question": "How many undefeated fights had Mike Tyson before losing he's first fight?",
            "options": [
                "41",
                "32",
                "39",
                "37"
            ],
            "answer": "37",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 229,
            "question": "A molecule that has both polar and nonpolar regions is called ",
            "options": [
                "Amphipathic ",
                "Hydrophilic ",
                "Hydrophobic ",
                "Hydrated "
            ],
            "answer": "Amphipathic ",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 70,
            "question": "What is the color of Donald Duck's bowtie?",
            "options": [
                "Red",
                "Blue",
                "Green",
                "Yellow "
            ],
            "answer": "Red",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 48,
            "question": "Which actor does not appear in 'Saving Private Ryan'?",
            "options": [
                "Tom Hanks",
                "Vin Diesel",
                "Ralph Fiennes",
                "Giovanni Ribisi "
            ],
            "answer": "Ralph Fiennes",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 50,
            "question": "Which of these antagonist characters was created by novelist J.K. Rowling?",
            "options": [
                "Lord Farqaad",
                "Darth Vader",
                "Lord Voldemort",
                "Professor Moriarty "
            ],
            "answer": "Lord Voldemort",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 316,
            "question": "When Was the Ryder Cup First Played?",
            "options": [
                "1931",
                "1925",
                "1927",
                "1929"
            ],
            "answer": "1927",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 396,
            "question": "What country was Hitler born?",
            "options": [
                "Spain",
                "Germany",
                "Holland",
                "Austria "
            ],
            "answer": "Austria ",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 166,
            "question": "What is Romeo's last name?",
            "options": [
                "Montague",
                "Capulet",
                "Laurence",
                "Escalus"
            ],
            "answer": "Montague",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 98,
            "question": "Which of these is known as little Russia?",
            "options": [
                "Ukraine",
                "Finland",
                "Norway",
                "Kazakhstan"
            ],
            "answer": "Ukraine",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 247,
            "question": "Who's home ground is White Hart Lane?",
            "options": [
                "Charlton Athletic",
                "Bolton Wanderers",
                "Man Utd",
                "Tottenham Hotspur"
            ],
            "answer": "Tottenham Hotspur",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 39,
            "question": "What part of the body does a turtle use to breathe?",
            "options": [
                "Belly",
                "Shell",
                "Mouth",
                "Anus"
            ],
            "answer": "Anus",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 200,
            "question": "Who said \"Into the valley of Death Rode the six hundred\"",
            "options": [
                "Samuel Taylor Coleridge ",
                "William Shakespeare",
                "Edgar Allan Poe",
                "Alfred Lord Tennyson"
            ],
            "answer": "Alfred Lord Tennyson",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 54,
            "question": "Which of these cities is closest to London, UK?",
            "options": [
                "Boston, MA",
                "New York, NY",
                "Atlanta, GA",
                "Miami, FL "
            ],
            "answer": "Boston, MA",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 402,
            "question": "A ______ is worth a thousand words.",
            "options": [
                "Keyboard",
                "Letter",
                "Sound",
                "Picture"
            ],
            "answer": "Picture",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 333,
            "question": "In what city is the Golden Gate Bridge located?",
            "options": [
                "New York",
                "Atlanta",
                "Miami",
                "San Francisco"
            ],
            "answer": "San Francisco",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 148,
            "question": "Who wrote \"Lolita\"?",
            "options": [
                "Joseph Heller",
                "Vladimir Nabokov",
                "Thomas Merton",
                "Paul Bowles"
            ],
            "answer": "Vladimir Nabokov",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 269,
            "question": "Which year was Tyson vs Spinks ?",
            "options": [
                "1986",
                "1988",
                "1992",
                "1990"
            ],
            "answer": "1988",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 155,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Hitchhikers Guide to the Galaxy\"?",
            "options": [
                "Nicholas Evans",
                "Charles Dickens",
                "Douglas Adams",
                "Kenneth Grahame"
            ],
            "answer": "Douglas Adams",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 35,
            "question": "What are Lanthanides?",
            "options": [
                "Elements in the periodic table",
                "Mountains on Earth",
                "Mountains on the Moon",
                "Bacterium"
            ],
            "answer": "Elements in the periodic table",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 478,
            "question": "The god of the sea, rivers, floods, droughts, earthquakes, and the creator of horses; known as the \"Earth Shaker\".",
            "options": [
                "Hestia",
                "Poseidon",
                "Zeus",
                "Hera"
            ],
            "answer": "Poseidon",
            "category_id": 10
        },
        {
            "id": 273,
            "question": "Who holds the record for being the youngest boxing world champion in boxing ?",
            "options": [
                "Marco Antonio Barrera",
                "Mike Tyson",
                "Hector Camancho",
                "Wilfredo Benitez"
            ],
            "answer": "Wilfredo Benitez",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 305,
            "question": "Manny Pacquiao defeated Mosley, Hatton, De La Hoya, M\u00e1rquez, Barrera and Morales to name a few, what nationality is he?",
            "options": [
                "Mexican",
                "Filipino",
                "Cuban  ",
                "American "
            ],
            "answer": "Filipino",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 419,
            "question": "A bird in the hand is worth _______ in the bush",
            "options": [
                "Few",
                "Two",
                "More",
                "The same"
            ],
            "answer": "Two",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 33,
            "question": "Which singer once took a bite out of a Beach Boys record during a press conference?",
            "options": [
                "Robbie Williams",
                "Engelbert Humperdinck",
                "Shane McGowan",
                "James Blunt"
            ],
            "answer": "Shane McGowan",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 62,
            "question": "Which city's landmarks include: The Pantheon, The Spanish Steps and Trevi Fountain?",
            "options": [
                "Rome",
                "Athens",
                "Barcelona",
                "Istanbul "
            ],
            "answer": "Rome",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 328,
            "question": "The Colosseum completed in 80 AD and is located in the centre of which city?",
            "options": [
                "Paris",
                "Rome",
                "Istanbul",
                "Athens"
            ],
            "answer": "Rome",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 311,
            "question": "Rocky Marciano (September 1, 1923 \u2013 August 31, 1969) was an Italian-American boxer and the heavyweight champion of the world. Out of he's 49 professional fights how many did he lose?",
            "options": [
                "4",
                "1",
                "2",
                "0"
            ],
            "answer": "0",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 210,
            "question": "\"All that I have to say, is to tell you that the lantern is the moon; I, the man i' the moon; this thorn-bush, my thorn-bush; this dog, my dog.\" This extract is from a Shakespearean romantic comedy, often defined as a journey into fantasy and the surreal world. Name it.",
            "options": [
                "\"A Midsummer Night's Dream\" ",
                "\"Much Ado About Nothing\" ",
                "\"The Merry Wives of Windsor\"",
                "\"Love's Labour's Lost\" "
            ],
            "answer": "\"A Midsummer Night's Dream\" ",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 47,
            "question": "Which truck is produced by the Ford Motor Company?",
            "options": [
                "RAV4",
                "F-150",
                "Silverado 1500",
                "CR-V "
            ],
            "answer": "F-150",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 103,
            "question": "This book has witches, flying monkeys, a cowardly lion, and a girl who just wants to go home. What is the girl's name?",
            "options": [
                "Dorothy",
                "Lucy",
                "Alice",
                "Anthea"
            ],
            "answer": "Dorothy",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 289,
            "question": "Where was the World Cup held in 1986?",
            "options": [
                "Italy",
                "Mexico",
                "Argentina ",
                "Brazil"
            ],
            "answer": "Mexico",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 60,
            "question": "Which of these NBA franchises has never signed LeBron James?",
            "options": [
                "Los Angeles Lakers",
                "Cleveland Cavaliers",
                "Boston Celtics",
                "Miami Heat "
            ],
            "answer": "Boston Celtics",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 359,
            "question": "Which of these &#34;facts&#34; are associated with the Pearl Harbor Conspiracy?",
            "options": [
                "A. the Japanese attacked Pearl Harbor, which held American bases",
                "B. the Japanese were allies of the U.S.",
                "C. the Japanese were allowed to attack the Americans in order to drag them into the war",
                "E. Churchhill did not tell Roosevelt, since he was desperate to get Americans into the war to help the British"
            ],
            "answer": "E. Churchhill did not tell Roosevelt, since he was desperate to get Americans into the war to help the British",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 194,
            "question": "With both his parents dead, young David Balfour sets out to learn the truth about his rightful inheritance. His cruel uncle Ebenezer wants David gone, and arranges for him to be spirited away and sold into slavery. Robert Louis Stevenson is the author of this book about David's adventures and the people he meets in his quest for justice. What's the name of this book, which was published in 1886?",
            "options": [
                "Treasure Island",
                "The Master of Ballantrae",
                "Kidnapped",
                "The Ebb-Tide"
            ],
            "answer": "Kidnapped",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 244,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Goodison Park?",
            "options": [
                "Leeds United",
                "Burnley",
                "Sheffield United FC",
                "Everton"
            ],
            "answer": "Everton",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 91,
            "question": "Who was John Cleese married to?",
            "options": [
                "Amy Kingman",
                "Connie Booth",
                "Audrey Palmer",
                "Doris Shephall"
            ],
            "answer": "Connie Booth",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 198,
            "question": "O Captain! My Captain! ",
            "options": [
                "Khalil Gibran ",
                "Maya Angelou",
                "Walt Whitman",
                "Emily Dickinson"
            ],
            "answer": "Walt Whitman",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 201,
            "question": "Who said \"I Do Not Love You Except Because I Love You\"",
            "options": [
                "Emily Dickinson",
                "William Wordsworth",
                "Khalil Gibran ",
                "Pablo Neruda"
            ],
            "answer": "Pablo Neruda",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 177,
            "question": "How are Tybalt and Juliet related?",
            "options": [
                "They aren't related",
                "Tybalt is her uncle",
                "They're cousins",
                "They're brother and sister"
            ],
            "answer": "They're cousins",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 110,
            "question": "In J.R.R. Tolkien's \"The Hobbit\", Bilbo Baggins and a band of dwarves set off to steal a treasure from a dragon. What is the dragon's name?",
            "options": [
                "Smaug",
                "Jormungand",
                "Nidhogg",
                "Fafnir"
            ],
            "answer": "Smaug",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 370,
            "question": "it was created to determine the right time and place to set up a new society, one that would replace the collapsing Galactic Empire by sheer force of social pressure, but over only a thousand-year time span, rather than the ten-to-thirty-thousand-year time span that would normally have been required, and thus reduce the human suffering from living in a time of barbarism.<br/>",
            "options": [
                "A. Psychohistory",
                "C. Sea Life Centre in Oberhausen, Germany",
                "D. Moore's Law.",
                "B. The Seldon Plan"
            ],
            "answer": "B. The Seldon Plan",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 298,
            "question": "Who won the first world cup?",
            "options": [
                "Uruguay ",
                "Brazil",
                "Argentina",
                "Spain"
            ],
            "answer": "Uruguay ",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 20,
            "question": "Anemophobia is the fear of what?",
            "options": [
                "Spiders",
                "The Dark",
                "Fire",
                "Wind"
            ],
            "answer": "Wind",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 231,
            "question": "The lipid bilayer is composed primarily of what two biological molecules? ",
            "options": [
                "Sugars and fats ",
                "Proteins and fats",
                "Carbohydrates and proteins ",
                "Sugars and protein"
            ],
            "answer": "Proteins and fats",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 429,
            "question": "Better to ______ a penny then lend twenty.",
            "options": [
                "Spend",
                "Find",
                "Give",
                "Lose"
            ],
            "answer": "Give",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 145,
            "question": "Who wrote \"Who Moved My Cheese\"? ",
            "options": [
                "Richard Bach",
                "Spencer Johnson",
                "James Redfield",
                "Nicholas Evans"
            ],
            "answer": "Spencer Johnson",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 113,
            "question": "In this book, a boy named Bastian becomes involved in a quest to save Fantasia. In fact, Bastian actually ENTERS the book. ",
            "options": [
                "The Secret World of Og",
                "The Never-Ending Story",
                "The Ogre Downstairs",
                "The Island of the Aunts"
            ],
            "answer": "The Never-Ending Story",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 271,
            "question": "Who was the oldest fighter to compete for a world title ?",
            "options": [
                "Evander Holyfield",
                "Ezzard Charles",
                "Thomas Hearns",
                "Roberto Duran"
            ],
            "answer": "Roberto Duran",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 296,
            "question": "Who is this?",
            "options": [
                "Cantona",
                "Platini",
                "Zidane",
                "Deschamps"
            ],
            "answer": "Platini",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 486,
            "question": "The god of war, bloodlust, violence, manly courage, and civil order.",
            "options": [
                "Ares",
                "Athena",
                "Zeus",
                "Dionysus"
            ],
            "answer": "Ares",
            "category_id": 10
        },
        {
            "id": 232,
            "question": "Which of the following best describes the properties of a lipid-bound protein?",
            "options": [
                " Having its tail-end attached to the lipid bilayer",
                "Being entirely located in the lipid bilayer ",
                "Being loosely associated with the lipid bilayer ",
                "Having its head-end attached to the lipid bilayer "
            ],
            "answer": "Being entirely located in the lipid bilayer ",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 100,
            "question": "What kind of animal is Reepicheep?",
            "options": [
                "A lion",
                "A centaur",
                "A mouse",
                "A bear"
            ],
            "answer": "A mouse",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 403,
            "question": "One joy scatters a hundred ______.",
            "options": [
                "Griefs",
                "Times",
                "Fears",
                "Lives"
            ],
            "answer": "Griefs",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 128,
            "question": "Who wrote \"On Death and Dying\"?",
            "options": [
                "Agatha Christie",
                "Charles Dickens",
                "Spencer Johnson",
                "Elisabeth K\u00fcbler-Ross"
            ],
            "answer": "Elisabeth K\u00fcbler-Ross",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 385,
            "question": "Who was the first Roman Empire?",
            "options": [
                "Julius Caesar ",
                "Claudius",
                "Nero",
                "Augustus"
            ],
            "answer": "Augustus",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 365,
            "question": "What is true about the Chemist's War?",
            "options": [
                "A. it happened in the U.S. during Prohibition",
                "B. it led to Guy Fawke's imprisonment",
                "C. the U.S. poisoned alcohol",
                "E. It resulted in 10,000 deaths"
            ],
            "answer": "E. It resulted in 10,000 deaths",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 230,
            "question": "Which of the following are not a cytoskeletal protein filament?",
            "options": [
                "Microtubules ",
                "Intermediate filaments ",
                "Primary filaments ",
                "Actin "
            ],
            "answer": "Primary filaments ",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 401,
            "question": "______ from the hip.",
            "options": [
                "Lean",
                "Stare",
                "Draw",
                "Shoot"
            ],
            "answer": "Shoot",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 383,
            "question": "Which of these Roman Emperors was assassinated in a conspiracy involving senators in 41AD?",
            "options": [
                "Caesar ",
                "Tiberius",
                "Nero",
                "Caligula"
            ],
            "answer": "Caligula",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 257,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Emirates Stadium?",
            "options": [
                "West Ham United",
                "Leeds United",
                "Norwich",
                "Arsenal"
            ],
            "answer": "Arsenal",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 293,
            "question": "How many times did Liverpool win the European Cup/UEFA Champions League?",
            "options": [
                "6",
                "4",
                "3",
                "5"
            ],
            "answer": "5",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 368,
            "question": "in many naturally occurring collections of numbers, the leading significant digit is likely to be small.<br/>",
            "options": [
                "B. superposition",
                "C. P\u0101ora Te Potangaroa",
                "D. Anthropic Principle",
                "A. Benford's Law"
            ],
            "answer": "A. Benford's Law",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 277,
            "question": "Which boxing match was billed as 'One for the Ages' ?",
            "options": [
                "Holmes vs Tyson",
                "Hagler vs Hearns",
                "Barrera vs Hamed",
                "Foreman vs Moorer"
            ],
            "answer": "Foreman vs Moorer",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 136,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Horse Whisperer\"?",
            "options": [
                "Dorothy Allison",
                "Agatha Christie",
                "Spencer Johnson",
                "Nicholas Evans"
            ],
            "answer": "Nicholas Evans",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 322,
            "question": "How manny balls are there on a snooker table? ",
            "options": [
                "17",
                "23",
                "18",
                "22"
            ],
            "answer": "22",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 131,
            "question": "Who wrote \"Le Petit Prince (The Little Prince)\"?",
            "options": [
                "Richard Bach",
                "James Redfield",
                "Ken Kesey",
                "Antoine de Saint-Exup\u00e9ry"
            ],
            "answer": "Antoine de Saint-Exup\u00e9ry",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 149,
            "question": "Who wrote \"Lord of the Rings\"?",
            "options": [
                "James Baldwin",
                "Charles Dickens",
                "Richard Bach",
                "J R R Tolkein"
            ],
            "answer": "J R R Tolkein",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 473,
            "question": " \"When one door closes, another opens - but we often look so long and so regretfully upon the closed door that we do not see the one which has opened for us.\" Who said this? ",
            "options": [
                "John Adams",
                "Thomas Edison",
                "Alexander Graham Bell",
                "Jack the Ripper"
            ],
            "answer": "Alexander Graham Bell",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 94,
            "question": "What is the Capital city of Switzerland?",
            "options": [
                "Geneva",
                "St.Gallen",
                "Zurich",
                "Bern"
            ],
            "answer": "Bern",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 65,
            "question": "According to Persian folklore, who is the storyteller of 'One Thousand and One Nights'?",
            "options": [
                "Scheherazade",
                "Kanaan",
                "Homer",
                "Hatshepsut "
            ],
            "answer": "Scheherazade",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 215,
            "question": "What is an Atom made out of?",
            "options": [
                "Protons and Neurons",
                "Protons, Neutrons and Electrons",
                "Neurons and Electrons",
                "Protons ,Neurons and Electrons"
            ],
            "answer": "Protons, Neutrons and Electrons",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 341,
            "question": "What city is the Eiffel Tower (AKA \"the iron lady\") located?",
            "options": [
                "Barcelona",
                "Madrid",
                "London",
                "Paris"
            ],
            "answer": "Paris",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 31,
            "question": "Who was the only English player to win the European Golden Boot award? ",
            "options": [
                "Robbie Fowler",
                "Michael Owen",
                "Gary Lineker",
                "Kevin Phillips"
            ],
            "answer": "Kevin Phillips",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 431,
            "question": "______ will tell.",
            "options": [
                "Life",
                "History",
                "Love",
                "Time"
            ],
            "answer": "Time",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 268,
            "question": "Name the boxer",
            "options": [
                "Thulani Malinga",
                "Pinklon Thomas",
                "Samuel Peter",
                "Carl Thompson"
            ],
            "answer": "Carl Thompson",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 337,
            "question": "Chichen Itza built by the Maya civilization between the 7th through 10th centuries is located in ...?",
            "options": [
                "Brazil",
                "Argentina",
                "Chile",
                "Mexico"
            ],
            "answer": "Mexico",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 95,
            "question": "Who is the Patron Saint of Spain?",
            "options": [
                "St James",
                "St George",
                "St John",
                "St peter"
            ],
            "answer": "St James",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 15,
            "question": "Hypermetropic people are what?",
            "options": [
                "obese",
                "underfed",
                "moody",
                "far sighted"
            ],
            "answer": "far sighted",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 116,
            "question": "How old is the retirement age for horses?",
            "options": [
                "8",
                "12",
                "10",
                "11"
            ],
            "answer": "12",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 164,
            "question": "Who wrote \"If You Meet the Buddha on the Road, Kill Him!\"?",
            "options": [
                "Sheldon B Kopp",
                "Richard Dawkins",
                "Charles Olson",
                "Eckhart Tolle"
            ],
            "answer": "Sheldon B Kopp",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 413,
            "question": "Bright eyed and ______ tailed.",
            "options": [
                "Busy",
                "Happy",
                "Fluffy",
                "Bushy"
            ],
            "answer": "Bushy",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 261,
            "question": "Who won the 1999 world cup?",
            "options": [
                "South Africa",
                "New Zealand",
                "Australia",
                "England"
            ],
            "answer": "Australia",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 175,
            "question": "What is Juliet's last name?",
            "options": [
                "Escalus",
                "Montague",
                "Capulet",
                "Laurence"
            ],
            "answer": "Capulet",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 460,
            "question": "\"ask not what your country can do for you - ask what you can do for your country\"",
            "options": [
                "John F. Kennedy",
                "Theodore Roosevelt",
                "George Bush",
                "Winston Churchill"
            ],
            "answer": "John F. Kennedy",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 434,
            "question": "______ it on the chin.",
            "options": [
                "Feel",
                "Make",
                "Take",
                "Lick"
            ],
            "answer": "Take",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 467,
            "question": "\"It's not whether you get knocked down - it's whether you get up.\" Which outstanding American coach of National Football League has been credited for this remark that could apply equally to all aspects of a person's life?",
            "options": [
                "Mickey Mantle",
                "Babe Ruth",
                "Vince Lombardi",
                "Tommy Lasorda"
            ],
            "answer": "Vince Lombardi",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 180,
            "question": "What is Paris's last request?",
            "options": [
                "To be buried in the tomb with Juliet",
                "To know all the truth",
                "He doesn't have a last request",
                "That Romeo suffer for his death"
            ],
            "answer": "To be buried in the tomb with Juliet",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 265,
            "question": "Where was the 1991 Rugby World Cup held?",
            "options": [
                "France",
                "South Africa",
                "Australia",
                "Great Britain, Ireland and France"
            ],
            "answer": "Great Britain, Ireland and France",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 249,
            "question": "Who's home ground is The Valley?",
            "options": [
                "Chelsea",
                "Newcastle United",
                "Millwall",
                "Charlton Athletic"
            ],
            "answer": "Charlton Athletic",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 139,
            "question": "Who wrote \"La Sombra del Viento (The Shadow of the Wind)\"?",
            "options": [
                "John Steinbeck",
                "Dr Arthjur Janov",
                "Joseph Heller",
                "Carlos Ruiz Zaf\u00f3n"
            ],
            "answer": "Carlos Ruiz Zaf\u00f3n",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 209,
            "question": "\"I am the man! If it be so,--as tis,--poor lady, she were better love a dream.\" These words belong to Viola, who is disguised as a man, in what Shakespearean play?",
            "options": [
                "\"A Comedy of Errors\" ",
                "\"Troilus and Cressida\"",
                "\"Much Ado About Nothing\" ",
                "\"Twelfth Night\" "
            ],
            "answer": "\"Twelfth Night\" ",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 49,
            "question": "How many spaces are on a standard Monopoly board?",
            "options": [
                "20",
                "40",
                "60",
                "80 "
            ],
            "answer": "40",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 270,
            "question": "Which boxer has the longest reign as welterweight champion ?",
            "options": [
                "Julio Cesar Chavez",
                "Harry Greb",
                "Ray Leonard",
                "Felix Trinidad"
            ],
            "answer": "Felix Trinidad",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 360,
            "question": "Which of these were all part of the Gunpowder Plot?",
            "options": [
                "A.  to assassinate King James I of England and VI of Scotlandt",
                "B. to burn Buckingham Palace",
                "C.  to kidnap the royal children",
                "D. to lead a popular revolt in the Midlands"
            ],
            "answer": "D. to lead a popular revolt in the Midlands",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 321,
            "question": "What is the weight of a discus?",
            "options": [
                "Men 2.5kg, women 2kg ",
                "For men and women 2kg",
                "Men 3kg, women 2kg ",
                "Men 2kg, women 1kg "
            ],
            "answer": "Men 2kg, women 1kg ",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 304,
            "question": "Which undefeated American boxer born 1977 has over 40 profession fights and is also know as \"Pretty Boy\"?",
            "options": [
                "Shane Mosley",
                "David D\u00edaz",
                "Antonio Margarito",
                "Floyd Mayweather"
            ],
            "answer": "Floyd Mayweather",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 202,
            "question": "Who said \"There is another sky, Ever serene and fair\"",
            "options": [
                "Emily Dickinson",
                "Joyce Kilmer",
                "Julia Ward Howe",
                "Maya Angelou"
            ],
            "answer": "Emily Dickinson",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 334,
            "question": "Machu Piccu nestled 7,500 feet above sea level was created around 1450 by which famous empire?",
            "options": [
                "Persian",
                "Greeks",
                "Egyptians",
                "Incas"
            ],
            "answer": "Incas",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 106,
            "question": "In \"The Lion, the Witch, and the Wardrobe\", what is Lucy doing when she first discovers the magical wardrobe?",
            "options": [
                "Packing to leave",
                "Exploring the house",
                "Cleaning",
                "Hanging up clothes"
            ],
            "answer": "Exploring the house",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 109,
            "question": "In this book, a girl has fallen down a rabbit hole, grown smaller and then larger, and is now at a very strange tea-party. Who keeps falling asleep at the party?",
            "options": [
                "The mock turtle",
                "The March Hare",
                "The Mad Hatter",
                "The dormouse"
            ],
            "answer": "The dormouse",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 89,
            "question": "What was the first game created",
            "options": [
                "A tennis game",
                "Pes 1962",
                "Sonic the hedgehog",
                "Mario bros"
            ],
            "answer": "A tennis game",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 299,
            "question": "How many world cups have Italy won?",
            "options": [
                "3",
                "5",
                "2",
                "4"
            ],
            "answer": "4",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 301,
            "question": "Who has won the most champions leagues?",
            "options": [
                "AC Milan ",
                "Real Madrid",
                "Liverpool",
                "Man Utd"
            ],
            "answer": "Real Madrid",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 158,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Power of Now\"?",
            "options": [
                "Maxine Hong",
                "Douglas Adams",
                "Eckhart Tolle",
                "Elisabeth K\u00fcbler-Ross"
            ],
            "answer": "Eckhart Tolle",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 443,
            "question": "Who let the ______ out of the bag?",
            "options": [
                "Mouse",
                "Dog",
                "Horse",
                "Cat"
            ],
            "answer": "Cat",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 12,
            "question": "What is the more usual name for Roentgen Rays?",
            "options": [
                "X Rays",
                "Gamma Rays",
                "Ultraviolet Rays",
                "Magnetic Resonance"
            ],
            "answer": "X Rays",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 435,
            "question": "Take the ______ by the horns.",
            "options": [
                "Mule",
                "Bull",
                "Deer",
                "Cow"
            ],
            "answer": "Bull",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 423,
            "question": "Do not speak of ______ in a field that is full of little hills.",
            "options": [
                "Danger",
                "Faults",
                "Secrets",
                "Lies"
            ],
            "answer": "Secrets",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 150,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Wind in the Willows\"?",
            "options": [
                "Kenneth Grahame",
                "James Redfield",
                "Dorothy Allison",
                "Charles Dickens"
            ],
            "answer": "Kenneth Grahame",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 352,
            "question": "Which are true about the Long March?",
            "options": [
                "A. It was a  military retreat undertaken by the Red Army of the communist Party of China, .",
                "B. It was taken to evade the pursuit of the Chinese Nationalist Party army",
                "C. It  Lasted 368 days and covered 6,000 miles.",
                "D. It involved 86,000 troops, 15.000 personnel, and 35 women."
            ],
            "answer": "D. It involved 86,000 troops, 15.000 personnel, and 35 women.",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 56,
            "question": "How many blue stripes does the United States of America national flag have?",
            "options": [
                "0",
                "6",
                "7",
                "13 "
            ],
            "answer": "0",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 43,
            "question": "What is the largest country, by area, that has only one time zone?",
            "options": [
                "Russia",
                "China",
                "Turkey",
                "Australia "
            ],
            "answer": "China",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 228,
            "question": "Which of the following phrases best matches the definition of the term hydrophobic?",
            "options": [
                "\"water-loving\" ",
                "\"water-hating\" ",
                "\"water-impartial\" ",
                " \"water-storing\" "
            ],
            "answer": "\"water-hating\" ",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 357,
            "question": "Aside from Lee Harvey Oswald, which of these were among those who might have killed JFK?",
            "options": [
                "A. CIA assassins: on motorcades when the shooting happened",
                "B. the Mafia, the KGB or the Illuminati",
                "C. the Little Green Men: masked soldiers carrying Russian weapons",
                "E. a man with a black umbrella"
            ],
            "answer": "E. a man with a black umbrella",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 10,
            "question": "How many earths would fit inside the sun?",
            "options": [
                "circa 100",
                "circa 1,000,000",
                "circa 10,000",
                "circa 100,000"
            ],
            "answer": "circa 1,000,000",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 237,
            "question": "The function of the cytoskeleton is most similar to the function of what other cellular structure? ",
            "options": [
                "Peroxisome ",
                "Cytoplasm ",
                "Lipid bilayer ",
                "Mitochondria "
            ],
            "answer": "Lipid bilayer ",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 135,
            "question": "Who wrote \"How to Win Friends and Influence People\"?",
            "options": [
                "Nathanael West",
                "Richard Bach",
                "Dale Carnegie",
                "George Orwell"
            ],
            "answer": "Dale Carnegie",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 300,
            "question": "Argentina Won the world cup in which years?",
            "options": [
                "1970",
                "1982",
                "1978",
                "1986"
            ],
            "answer": "1986",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 17,
            "question": "Which NHL hockey team has won the most Stanley Cups?",
            "options": [
                "Toronto Maple Leafs",
                "Boston Bruins",
                "Montreal Canadiens",
                "New York Rangers"
            ],
            "answer": "Montreal Canadiens",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 223,
            "question": "Which of the following eukaryotic intracellular components are not organelles? ",
            "options": [
                "Lysosomes",
                "Cytoskeleton",
                "Golgi apparatus ",
                "ER"
            ],
            "answer": "Cytoskeleton",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 213,
            "question": "\"Blow winds, and crack your cheeks! Rage! Blow!\" The tragedy, this line was extracted from is based on a legend, that had been mentioned in numerous chronicles, poems, and sermons, before Shakespeare created his interpretation of it.",
            "options": [
                "\"The Tempest\" ",
                "\"Twelfth Night\" ",
                "\"Macbeth\" ",
                "\"King Lear\""
            ],
            "answer": "\"King Lear\"",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 421,
            "question": "Heaven lent you a soul Earth will lend a ______.",
            "options": [
                "Home",
                "Hand",
                "Grave",
                "Place"
            ],
            "answer": "Grave",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 274,
            "question": "Which boxer had the most title fights ?",
            "options": [
                "Muhammad Ali",
                "Archie Moore",
                "Ray Leonard",
                "Julio Cesar Chavez"
            ],
            "answer": "Julio Cesar Chavez",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 260,
            "question": "Who did  South Africa beat in the 2007 world cup final?",
            "options": [
                "Australia",
                "France",
                "New Zealand",
                "England"
            ],
            "answer": "England",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 461,
            "question": "Watch your thoughts; they become words.\r\nWatch your words; they become actions.\r\nWatch your actions; they become habits.\r\nWatch your habits; they become character.\r\nWatch your character; it becomes your destiny.",
            "options": [
                "Aristotle",
                "Confucius",
                "Lao Tzu",
                "Socrates "
            ],
            "answer": "Lao Tzu",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 191,
            "question": "Dorothy Gale, a young girl living in Kansas, is swept away by a cyclone and dropped into a fantasy land. She meets a man made of tin, a lion who's a big fraidy cat and a scarecrow who believes he lacks a brain. Dorothy is seeking a powerful wizard to grant her one wish, to return home. To which city must Dorothy travel to find the wizard? ",
            "options": [
                "Diamond City",
                "Ruby City",
                "City of Gold",
                "Emerald City"
            ],
            "answer": "Emerald City",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 235,
            "question": "The term hydrophilic means which of the following? ",
            "options": [
                "Attracted to water ",
                "Insoluble in water ",
                "Non-water containing ",
                "Repelled by water "
            ],
            "answer": "Attracted to water ",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 67,
            "question": "Which of these countries was not a Soviet Republic in USSR?",
            "options": [
                "Moldova",
                "Serbia",
                "Azerbaijan",
                "Kyrgyzstan "
            ],
            "answer": "Serbia",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 85,
            "question": "What was the first Sonic Game that came out?",
            "options": [
                "Sonic Mania",
                "Sonic the Hedgehog",
                "Sonic the Hedgehog Classic Hereos",
                "Sonic Adventures 1"
            ],
            "answer": "Sonic the Hedgehog",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 162,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Lion, the Witch and the Wardrobe\"?",
            "options": [
                "Dr Benjamin Spock",
                "Theodore Dreiser",
                "Don Miguel Ruiz",
                "C S Lewis"
            ],
            "answer": "C S Lewis",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 444,
            "question": "Let's ______ the town red.",
            "options": [
                "Spray",
                "Colour",
                "Paint",
                "Make"
            ],
            "answer": "Paint",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 190,
            "question": "An adventurous boy plays hooky from school, and is made to whitewash a fence for his mischief. The boy and his friends witness a murder in a graveyard, run away to become \"pirates\", get lost in a cave. Mark Twain is the creator of this story, which has been a favorite of kids and adults for over 100 years. In which classic 1876 novel do these events take place? ",
            "options": [
                "Life on the Mississippi",
                "The Tragedy of Pudd'nhead Wilson",
                "The Adventures of Tom Sawyer",
                "A Connecticut Yankee in King Arthur's Court"
            ],
            "answer": "The Adventures of Tom Sawyer",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 114,
            "question": "In E. Nesbit's novel \"Five Children and It\", what is \"It\"?",
            "options": [
                "A flying carpet",
                "A treasure",
                "A sand fairy",
                "A magic ring"
            ],
            "answer": "A sand fairy",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 441,
            "question": "That's ______ for the course.",
            "options": [
                "Normal",
                "Par",
                "Far",
                "Darn"
            ],
            "answer": "Par",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 52,
            "question": "In which language was the book 'War and Peace' originally written?",
            "options": [
                "English",
                "Russian",
                "French",
                "German "
            ],
            "answer": "Russian",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 350,
            "question": "Which language is most spoken in the world?<br/>",
            "options": [
                "English",
                "Chinese",
                "Spanish",
                "French"
            ],
            "answer": "Chinese",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 115,
            "question": "Which historical figure does Snowball best resemble?",
            "options": [
                "Stalin",
                "Bukharin ",
                "Lenin",
                "Trotsky"
            ],
            "answer": "Trotsky",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 178,
            "question": "Why does Lord Capulet threaten to disown Juliet?",
            "options": [
                "She isn't upset over Tybalt",
                "She plans to move to Mantua",
                "She married Romeo behind his back and confronted him about it",
                "She won't follow her father's arranged marriage plans"
            ],
            "answer": "She won't follow her father's arranged marriage plans",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 118,
            "question": "Which animal spreads stories about Sugarcandy Mountain?",
            "options": [
                "Moses",
                "Squealer",
                "Mollie ",
                "Muriel"
            ],
            "answer": "Moses",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 188,
            "question": "No quiz about books for young people would be complete without mentioning Louisa May Alcott's classic novel \"Little Women.\" It's the story of four sisters and their close-knit family life, which takes place around the time of the American Civil War. What are the names of the four March sisters? ",
            "options": [
                "Allegra, Emily, Jennie, Rosalind",
                "Meg, Jo, Beth, Amy",
                "Mary, Ellen, Frances, Virginia",
                "Annabelle, Charlotte, Maud, Phillipa"
            ],
            "answer": "Meg, Jo, Beth, Amy",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 78,
            "question": "Epsom (England) is the place associated with",
            "options": [
                "Cricket",
                "Football",
                "Polo",
                "Horse racing"
            ],
            "answer": "Horse racing",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 332,
            "question": "Donghai bridge build in 2005 connects Shanghai and Yangshan Island, what is its length?",
            "options": [
                "20 Km",
                "32 Km",
                "24 Km",
                "28 Km"
            ],
            "answer": "32 Km",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 38,
            "question": "On what make of motorcycle did Barry Sheene win the 500cc-world title in 1977?",
            "options": [
                "Kawasaki",
                "Suzuki",
                "Mitsubishi",
                "Yamaha"
            ],
            "answer": "Suzuki",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 462,
            "question": "\"We must become the change we want to see\"",
            "options": [
                "George Washington",
                "Mahatma Gandhi",
                "Theodore Roosevelt",
                "Mother Teresa"
            ],
            "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 285,
            "question": "Which of these boxing movies is the odd one out ?",
            "options": [
                "The Fighter",
                "Raging Bull",
                "Somebody Up There Likes Me",
                "Rocky"
            ],
            "answer": "Rocky",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 324,
            "question": "What means a blue flag at the racecircuit?",
            "options": [
                "It's not permitted to overtake a car. ",
                "The race is stopped ",
                "There is danger on the track ",
                "You have to let a faster car pass"
            ],
            "answer": "You have to let a faster car pass",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 93,
            "question": "What is the best-selling Album of all time?",
            "options": [
                "Elton John - Made in England",
                "ACDC - Back in Black",
                "Take That - The Circus",
                "Michael Jackson - Thriller"
            ],
            "answer": "Michael Jackson - Thriller",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 297,
            "question": "Who has scored the most goals in world cup history?",
            "options": [
                "Pele",
                "Maradona",
                "Ronaldo Nazario de Lima",
                "Johan Cruyff"
            ],
            "answer": "Ronaldo Nazario de Lima",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 205,
            "question": "Who said \"But I have promises to keep,And miles to go before I sleep\" ",
            "options": [
                "William Shakespeare",
                "Robert Frost",
                "Alfred Lord Tennyson",
                "Edgar Allan Poe"
            ],
            "answer": "Robert Frost",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 390,
            "question": "What year was the Roman Empire's maximal extent (territorial)? ",
            "options": [
                "100 BC",
                "120 AD",
                "50 AD",
                "250 AD"
            ],
            "answer": "120 AD",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 68,
            "question": "What temperature is the same in Celsius and Fahrenheit?",
            "options": [
                "+100\u00b0",
                "+40\u00b0",
                "-40\u00b0",
                "0\u00b0 "
            ],
            "answer": "-40\u00b0",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 483,
            "question": "The king of the gods, the ruler of Mount Olympus and the god of the sky, weather, thunder, law, order, and fate.",
            "options": [
                "Athena",
                "Dionysus",
                "Zeus",
                "Hephaestus"
            ],
            "answer": "Zeus",
            "category_id": 10
        },
        {
            "id": 266,
            "question": "Who was the first boxer ever to recieve a million dollar purse ?",
            "options": [
                "Muhammad Ali",
                "Rocky Marciano",
                "Joe Louis",
                "Sonny Liston"
            ],
            "answer": "Sonny Liston",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 46,
            "question": "What restaurant franchise advises you to 'Eat Fresh'?",
            "options": [
                "Subway",
                "McDonald's",
                "KFC",
                "Taco Bell "
            ],
            "answer": "Subway",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 157,
            "question": "Who wrote \"Das Parfum (Perfume)\"?",
            "options": [
                "Theodore Dreiser",
                "Patrick S\u00fcskind",
                "Eckhart Tolle",
                "Erica Jong"
            ],
            "answer": "Patrick S\u00fcskind",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 163,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Secret\"?",
            "options": [
                "Toni Morrison",
                "James Redfield",
                "Agatha Christie",
                "Rhonda Byrne"
            ],
            "answer": "Rhonda Byrne",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 242,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Selhurst Park?",
            "options": [
                "Millwall",
                "Newcastle United",
                "Charlton Athletic",
                "Crystal Palace"
            ],
            "answer": "Crystal Palace",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 121,
            "question": "What are Boxer's two maxims?",
            "options": [
                "\"Four legs good, two legs better\" and \"Napolean is always right\" ",
                "\"I will work harder\" and \"Clover is always right\"",
                "\"I will work harder\" and \"Napolean is always right\"",
                "\"I will work harder\" and \"Two legs good, four legs bad\""
            ],
            "answer": "\"I will work harder\" and \"Napolean is always right\"",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 306,
            "question": "Who was the first fighter to defeat Muhammad Ali?",
            "options": [
                "Ken Norton",
                "Leon Spinks",
                "Ernie Terrell",
                "Joe Frazier"
            ],
            "answer": "Joe Frazier",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 484,
            "question": "The god of music, healing, plague, prophecies, poetry, and archery; associated with light, truth and the sun.",
            "options": [
                "Athena",
                "Ares",
                "Athena",
                "Apollo"
            ],
            "answer": "Apollo",
            "category_id": 10
        },
        {
            "id": 351,
            "question": "Which country does not have a desert?<br/>",
            "options": [
                "Russia",
                "United States",
                "Chile",
                "Australia"
            ],
            "answer": "Russia",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 141,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Phantom Tollbooth\"?",
            "options": [
                "Charles Dickens",
                "Raymond Carver",
                "Norton Juster",
                "Dorothy Allison"
            ],
            "answer": "Norton Juster",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 335,
            "question": "Red Square is often considered the central square of the city and the country is located in ...?",
            "options": [
                "Rome, Italy",
                "Paris, France",
                "Warsaw, Poland",
                "Moscow, Russia "
            ],
            "answer": "Moscow, Russia ",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 256,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Old Trafford?",
            "options": [
                "Crystal Palace",
                "West Ham United",
                "Newcastle United",
                "Man Utd"
            ],
            "answer": "Man Utd",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 259,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Craven Cottage?",
            "options": [
                "Burnley",
                "Man City",
                "Charlton Athletic",
                "Fulham FC"
            ],
            "answer": "Fulham FC",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 173,
            "question": "Who finds Juliet \"dead\" in her bed?",
            "options": [
                "Lady Capulet",
                "Lord Capulet",
                "The Nurse",
                "Romeo"
            ],
            "answer": "The Nurse",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 30,
            "question": "Julius Caesar said \"The die is cast\" after crossing which river?",
            "options": [
                "Danube",
                "Rubicon",
                "Thames",
                "Tiber"
            ],
            "answer": "Rubicon",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 349,
            "question": "What is a capital city of Canada?<br/>",
            "options": [
                "Montreal",
                "Vanqouver",
                "Ottawa",
                "Toronto"
            ],
            "answer": "Ottawa",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 112,
            "question": "In \"Half Magic\", by Edward Eager, the children discover a magic ...?",
            "options": [
                "Ring",
                "Genie",
                "Spell",
                "Coin"
            ],
            "answer": "Coin",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 354,
            "question": "Michael Barkun's conspiracy theories are based on these principles",
            "options": [
                "A. nothing happens by accident",
                "B. nothing is as it seems",
                "C. nothing lasts forever",
                "D. everything is connected"
            ],
            "answer": "D. everything is connected",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 361,
            "question": "Which of these are true about Cassandra?",
            "options": [
                "A. she was the daughter of Priam (last king of Troy) and Hecuba",
                "B. she predicted the fall of Troy",
                "C. she composed Drops of Jupiter",
                "D. she predicted the death of Agamemnon"
            ],
            "answer": "D. she predicted the death of Agamemnon",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 407,
            "question": "It was a ______ of the tongue.",
            "options": [
                "Tip",
                "Trip",
                "Snip",
                "Slip"
            ],
            "answer": "Slip",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 477,
            "question": "The goddess of wisdom, warfare, battle strategy, heroic endeavour, handicrafts and reason.",
            "options": [
                "Hephaestus",
                "Pluto/Hades",
                "Athena",
                "Dionysus"
            ],
            "answer": "Athena",
            "category_id": 10
        },
        {
            "id": 108,
            "question": "Under Platform 13, at King's Cross Railway Station, is a gump. What IS a gump?",
            "options": [
                "An ogre",
                "A pile of weapons",
                "A kind of chewing gum",
                "A hidden door to a different world"
            ],
            "answer": "A hidden door to a different world",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 392,
            "question": "Who invented the light bulb?",
            "options": [
                "Einstein ",
                "Franklin",
                "Newton",
                "Edison"
            ],
            "answer": "Edison",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 245,
            "question": "Who's home ground is Anfield?",
            "options": [
                "Norwich",
                "Newcastle United",
                "Charlton Athletic",
                "Liverpool"
            ],
            "answer": "Liverpool",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 454,
            "question": "\"The gods too are fond of a joke\"",
            "options": [
                "Confucius",
                "Socrates ",
                "Lao Tzu",
                "Aristotle"
            ],
            "answer": "Aristotle",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 107,
            "question": "A boy called Wart is taken under the wing of a wizard, who turns him into all sorts of creatures, in order to further his education. In the end, the boy discovers his destiny. What is the book? ",
            "options": [
                "The Never-Ending Story",
                "Rewards and Fairies",
                "The Sword in the Stone",
                "The Twits"
            ],
            "answer": "The Sword in the Stone",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 465,
            "question": "\"To know even one life has breathed easier because you have lived - this is to have succeeded.\" Which poet and writer said this?",
            "options": [
                "F. Scott Fitzgerald",
                "William Wordsworth",
                "Ralph Waldo Emerson",
                "William Shakespeare"
            ],
            "answer": "Ralph Waldo Emerson",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 409,
            "question": "Like taking ______ from a baby.",
            "options": [
                "Cookies",
                "Milk",
                "Money",
                "Candy"
            ],
            "answer": "Candy",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 398,
            "question": "What was the name of the women who supposedly cause the Trojan war?",
            "options": [
                "Patricia",
                "Maria",
                "Mary",
                "Helen"
            ],
            "answer": "Helen",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 471,
            "question": "\"Be the change that you want to see in the world.\" Who was the great Indian leader who said this?",
            "options": [
                "Geronimo",
                "Sitting Bull",
                "Hiawatha",
                "Mohandas Gandhi"
            ],
            "answer": "Mohandas Gandhi",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 156,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The Primal Scream\"?",
            "options": [
                "Agatha Christie",
                "Nicholas Evans",
                "Dr Arthjur Janov",
                "Joseph Heller"
            ],
            "answer": "Dr Arthjur Janov",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 122,
            "question": "Which animal was motherly?",
            "options": [
                "Mollie",
                "Clover",
                "Boxer",
                "Moses"
            ],
            "answer": "Clover",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 34,
            "question": "Who was the first band to play at the Cavern Club?",
            "options": [
                "Swinging Blue Jeans",
                "The Merseysippi",
                "The Beatles",
                "Merseybeats"
            ],
            "answer": "The Merseysippi",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 287,
            "question": "Which boxer gave Muhammad Ali his second defeat ?",
            "options": [
                "Trevor Berbick",
                "Ernie Shavers",
                "Joe Frazier",
                "Ken Norton"
            ],
            "answer": "Ken Norton",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 463,
            "question": "\"Be slow to fall into friendship; but when thou art in, continue firm and constant\"",
            "options": [
                "Lao Tzu",
                "Socrates ",
                "Aristotle",
                "Confucius"
            ],
            "answer": "Socrates ",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 422,
            "question": "Deal with the ______ of others as gently as with your own.",
            "options": [
                "Cries",
                "Wives",
                "Faults",
                "Lies"
            ],
            "answer": "Faults",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 418,
            "question": "Slap on the ______.",
            "options": [
                "Face",
                "Backside",
                "Tongue",
                "Wrist"
            ],
            "answer": "Wrist",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 82,
            "question": "When was Minecraft created and who created it?",
            "options": [
                "It was made in 2011 and made by Notch",
                "It was made in 2007 and made by NOTCH",
                "It was made in 2009 and made by Microsoft XD",
                "It was made in 2011 and made by JEB"
            ],
            "answer": "It was made in 2011 and made by Notch",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 393,
            "question": "Where was Christopher Columbus born?",
            "options": [
                "Italy",
                "Spain",
                "Portugal",
                "France"
            ],
            "answer": "Italy",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 464,
            "question": "\"The smallest act of kindness is worth more than the grandest intention.\" Which playwright and poet made this remark?",
            "options": [
                "William Shakespeare",
                "William Wordsworth",
                "F. Scott Fitzgerald",
                "Oscar Wilde"
            ],
            "answer": "Oscar Wilde",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 329,
            "question": "The Grand Palace constructed in 1782 by King Rama I is located in which city?",
            "options": [
                "Beijing ",
                "Toyoko",
                "Hanoi",
                "Bangkok "
            ],
            "answer": "Bangkok ",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 212,
            "question": "\"O true apothecary! Thy drugs are quick.\" These are among the last words of a famous Shakespearean character, right before his tragic death, in which play?",
            "options": [
                "\"Hamlet\" ",
                "\"Romeo and Juliet\"",
                "\"Henry VIII\" ",
                "\"Julius Caesar\" "
            ],
            "answer": "\"Romeo and Juliet\"",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 292,
            "question": "Which of these players have won the most World Cups?",
            "options": [
                "Gary Lineker",
                "Pele",
                "Maradona",
                "Roy Keane"
            ],
            "answer": "Pele",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 475,
            "question": "The god of travel, messengers, trade, thievery, cunning wiles, language, writing, diplomacy, athletics, and animal husbandry. ",
            "options": [
                "Pluto/Hades",
                "Hermes",
                "Hephaestus",
                "Poseidon"
            ],
            "answer": "Hermes",
            "category_id": 10
        },
        {
            "id": 147,
            "question": "Who wrote \"The unbearable lightness of being\"?",
            "options": [
                "Linda Hogan",
                "Douglas Adams",
                "Eckhart Tolle",
                "Milan Kundera"
            ],
            "answer": "Milan Kundera",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 404,
            "question": "A Jack of all trades is master of ______.",
            "options": [
                "None",
                "Some",
                "Nothing",
                "Few"
            ],
            "answer": "None",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 214,
            "question": "What is an Atom?",
            "options": [
                "A small cell that is in everything",
                "The building block of life",
                "The building block within matter",
                "The building block of all matter"
            ],
            "answer": "The building block of all matter",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 192,
            "question": "One of the most beloved authors of children's stories has given us such tales as \"The Ugly Duckling\", \"The Little Mermaid\", \"The Emperor's New Clothes\" and \"The Snow Queen.\" Who was this Danish author?",
            "options": [
                "Hans Haakon Christoffersen",
                "Hans Frederick Jorgensen",
                "Hans Neils Christensen",
                "Hans Christian Andersen"
            ],
            "answer": "Hans Christian Andersen",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 51,
            "question": "Which of these chess figures is closely related to 'Bohemian Rhapsody'?",
            "options": [
                "King",
                "Queen",
                "Bishop",
                "Pawn "
            ],
            "answer": "Queen",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 291,
            "question": "Who has won the most league titles in top flight English football?",
            "options": [
                "Chelsea ",
                "Arsenal",
                "Man Utd",
                "Liverpool"
            ],
            "answer": "Man Utd",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 399,
            "question": "How many wives had kind Henry VIII?",
            "options": [
                "9",
                "7",
                "10",
                "6"
            ],
            "answer": "6",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 319,
            "question": "What is not a kind of horse sport?",
            "options": [
                "Polo ",
                "Voltige ",
                "Reining ",
                "Vasning "
            ],
            "answer": "Vasning ",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 284,
            "question": "Which boxer has the highest KO percentage rate in the history of the heavyweight division ?",
            "options": [
                "Ernie Shavers",
                "Mike Tyson",
                "George Foreman",
                "Vitali Klitschko"
            ],
            "answer": "Vitali Klitschko",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 152,
            "question": "Who wrote \"Catch-22\"?",
            "options": [
                "Raymond Carver",
                "James Baldwin",
                "Henry James",
                "Joseph Heller"
            ],
            "answer": "Joseph Heller",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 412,
            "question": "Half a loaf is better than ______",
            "options": [
                "Crumbs",
                "None",
                "Done",
                "Some"
            ],
            "answer": "None",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 453,
            "question": "\u201cAmerica will never be destroyed from the outside. If we falter and lose our freedoms, it will be because we destroyed ourselves\u201d ",
            "options": [
                "George Bush",
                "George Washington",
                "Abraham Lincoln",
                "Theodore Roosevelt"
            ],
            "answer": "Abraham Lincoln",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 427,
            "question": "To err is human to forgive is ______.",
            "options": [
                "Sublime",
                "Fine",
                "Divine",
                "A crime"
            ],
            "answer": "Divine",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 447,
            "question": "I had to burn the midnight ______.",
            "options": [
                "Candle",
                "Coil",
                "Soil",
                "Oil"
            ],
            "answer": "Oil",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 263,
            "question": "Which team is known as the Springboks?",
            "options": [
                "Australia ",
                "South African",
                "New Zealand",
                "Fiji"
            ],
            "answer": "South African",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 348,
            "question": "Which country was not originated from China?<br/>",
            "options": [
                "Taiwan",
                "Korea",
                "Singapore",
                "India"
            ],
            "answer": "India",
            "category_id": 4
        },
        {
            "id": 221,
            "question": "If an Atom loses an electron, what happens?",
            "options": [
                "It loses it electronic charge",
                "The atom is destroyed",
                "It becomes Negatively charged",
                "It becomes positively charged"
            ],
            "answer": "It becomes positively charged",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 88,
            "question": "In Minecraft how to craft a Redstone Repeater ?",
            "options": [
                "Redstone and Redstone torches",
                "2 cobblestone, 2 Redstone torches and 1 Redstone",
                "Just General Knowledge?",
                "3 stone, 1 Redstone torch and 2 Redstone"
            ],
            "answer": "3 stone, 1 Redstone torch and 2 Redstone",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 97,
            "question": "In what Country was former Prime Minister Tony Blair born?",
            "options": [
                "Wales",
                "Northern Ireland",
                "England",
                "Scotland"
            ],
            "answer": "Scotland",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 451,
            "question": "\"Et tu, Brute\"",
            "options": [
                "Julius Caesar",
                "Augustus",
                "Caligula",
                "Nero"
            ],
            "answer": "Julius Caesar",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 482,
            "question": "The crippled god of fire, metalworking, stonemasonry, sculpture and volcanism.",
            "options": [
                "Hermes",
                "Athena",
                "Hephaestus",
                "Hera"
            ],
            "answer": "Hephaestus",
            "category_id": 10
        },
        {
            "id": 127,
            "question": "Who wrote \"Love Story\"?",
            "options": [
                "Thomas Merton",
                "Edward Ball",
                "J D Salinger",
                "Erich Segal"
            ],
            "answer": "Erich Segal",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 225,
            "question": "Membrane proteins that cannot be easily removed from the cell membrane are called __________.",
            "options": [
                "Peripheral proteins ",
                "Locked proteins ",
                "Rigid proteins",
                "Integral proteins "
            ],
            "answer": "Integral proteins ",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 397,
            "question": "Who was the first president of America?",
            "options": [
                "Abraham Lincoln",
                "John Adams",
                "George Washington",
                "Thomas Jefferson"
            ],
            "answer": "George Washington",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 410,
            "question": "Let's get the ______ rolling.",
            "options": [
                "Stone",
                "Rock",
                "Wheel",
                "Ball"
            ],
            "answer": "Ball",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 233,
            "question": "Which of the following eukaryotic organelles is primarily responsible for cellular digestion?",
            "options": [
                "Golgi apparatus ",
                "Lysosome ",
                "Mitochondria ",
                "Nucleus "
            ],
            "answer": "Lysosome ",
            "category_id": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 84,
            "question": "What Game is sponsored by SEGA but isn't a Sonic Game",
            "options": [
                "Golden Axe",
                "Sanic",
                "Eliot the Kid",
                "Mario and Sonic at the Rio 2016 Olympic games"
            ],
            "answer": "Golden Axe",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 278,
            "question": "Which boxing class is heaviest ?",
            "options": [
                "Feather",
                "Bantam",
                "Straw",
                "Fly"
            ],
            "answer": "Feather",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 379,
            "question": "If you have a baby brother and he wants you to keep building a tower of blocks so he can tear it down, they you have something in common with...",
            "options": [
                "A. Pandora",
                "C. Remus",
                "D. Donald Trump",
                "B. Sisyphus"
            ],
            "answer": "B. Sisyphus",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 386,
            "question": "Who hoping to restore the constitutional government of the Republic was murdered by the senators on the Ides of March (15 March) 44 BC?",
            "options": [
                "Cicero",
                "Brutus",
                "Mark Anthony",
                "Julius Caesar"
            ],
            "answer": "Julius Caesar",
            "category_id": 5
        },
        {
            "id": 22,
            "question": "Timber selected from how many fully grown oak trees were needed to build a large 3 decker Royal Navy battle ship in the 18th century?",
            "options": [
                "50",
                "500",
                "1,500",
                "3,500"
            ],
            "answer": "3,500",
            "category_id": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 171,
            "question": "Who stabs Mercutio?",
            "options": [
                "Tybalt",
                "Peter",
                "Benvolio",
                "Romeo"
            ],
            "answer": "Tybalt",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 437,
            "question": "______ is the best policy.",
            "options": [
                "Generosity",
                "Honesty",
                "Kindness",
                "Sharing"
            ],
            "answer": "Honesty",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 438,
            "question": "I will leave no ______ unturned.",
            "options": [
                "Sock",
                "Pebble",
                "Rock",
                "Stone"
            ],
            "answer": "Stone",
            "category_id": 9
        },
        {
            "id": 281,
            "question": "How many defeats did Riddock Bowe have ?",
            "options": [
                "1",
                "7",
                "5",
                "3"
            ],
            "answer": "1",
            "category_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 174,
            "question": "What is the friar's plan for Juliet to avoid getting married to Paris?",
            "options": [
                "Tell her parents about her marriage with Romeo",
                "Leave Verona",
                "Stand up to her parents and tell them the truth",
                "A potion that will make her look dead"
            ],
            "answer": "A potion that will make her look dead",
            "category_id": 8
        },
        {
            "id": 317,
            "question": "In 2011 Rory McIlroy won the US Open, what score did he finish?",
            "options": [
                "19-under-par",
                "16-under-par",
                "13-under-par",
                "10-under-par"
            ],
            "answer": "16-under-par",
            "category_id": 2
        }
    ]
}